OK by now you've learned the interface and you've learned how to set up a project.
And now you should have the skills that you need to begin working with content begin developing an app
as you can see in this image here.
I've already sketched the kind of design that we're going to be creating inside a figure I sketched
this on my iPad and this is available in your assets folder as well as a PMG.
And now it's time to get our hands dirty adding some content.
So the first thing I'm going to do is go into Sigma here and in a previous video we already set up a
chef underscore a recipe on our sport app file.
But if you haven't done this yet you can just click on new file here and just started from scratch with
us.
If you do create a new file I'm just going to open up this file that we have your file name should say
untitled right here so to change that just click inside of this text area and you can name this whatever
you'd like.
So now we have this new fresh file here.
Any time that you'd like to you can go into the assets folder and find this PMG image and just open
it up for reference as we begin designing.
So the first thing we're going to do is set up five frames because we know those are the airports we're
going to start out with.
So you create new frames we can click on this frame tool here and rather than dragging a custom shape
like we're doing here is going to hit delete and we can go into here in the pre-sets and I know I'm
going to be designing for the iPhone 8.
So I'm just going to click on this preset here for an iPhone 8 frame.
Now if I hold down command and scroll down you can zoom out here.
And I'm just going to hold down option is I drag this for other times.
OK so now we have five our boards and one thing that you can do to make your frames even is hold down
shift and select all of them and then you can use this to distribute a horizontal spacing here.
So now we have some even spacing it looks really nice.
The next thing you want to do is name our frames so we can click on the name here.
And if the frame is blank you can always click inside of the frame to drag it around.
But once you add some content in here like a rectangle for example.
Now if I click inside of this area I can't drag it anymore.
I have to click on the name here to drag it around.
So I'll delete this.
Now let's just name our frames.
The first one is going to be the splash screen.
Second one is home.
Third is recipe
and I'll just name this recipe details.
And this will be recipe details complete
the last one here will name menu.
So we have our five our boards and you can drag these around very easily to reorder or reorganize them
as you're going along.
And now I can actually dragon select all of these.
Click on this distribute tool again and we're good to go.
Now a few shortcuts that you'll want to know is the number one on the keyboard.
We'll zoom everything into place and the numbers zero on the keyboard will zoom in to 100 percent.
So they're really nice toggles to jump back and forth in some zoom commands.
Now that we have these frames set up we want to enable a layout grid so to do that we can click and
then hold down shift and click the following objects here.
We can also click inside of the layers panel hold down shift and click the bottom layer to select all
of them and you can see here in the design panel we have a layout grid section that we can just click
this plus icon and instead of a grid here we can change the grid size to 15 pixels.
We can change the opacity of the look or we can jump into columns here and I'm going to change the column
count to 6 and I know I want the gutter to be 10 pixels in between the columns.
I also want a 10 pixel margin here and between the columns as well and I tend to find this red color
a little bit more pronounced than I'd like.
So I'm going to change the transparency here to 5 percent just to hide that a little bit more.
And now that I see this layout I'm thinking I probably want the edges of the frame here to have a 20
pixel margin for content so it's not writing right on the edge of that screen.
So we still have the 10 pixels here and between each column and this margin gives us 20 pixels on the
sides.
If you only select one of these and you edit the layout grid here there's no way to really copy that
style from this frame to this other one.
So it's very important as you are setting these up to set them all up in the frame are going to apply
to.
Now all of these frames are set to 375 pixels by 667 pixels and that's the device screen size for the
iPhone 8.
But there are times where your design is going to go beyond the device screen where you'll scroll up
and down so to resize these after they're created for example the home screen you can click and drag
this down and resize this.
So I like to start everything at the device screen high and then as I'm developing these shapes and
the styles if it starts to go past the screen you can quickly click and just drag down to increase your
frame size.
Also if you want to see more contrast between your frames in the background.
For example if your frame start out as gray You may not see a contrast here between the gray background
and the gray frame so you can always click on this background settings here and you can change this
down or you can change it to really whatever color you want.
But I like to have it just this like gray color here.