The components features one of my favorite features inside a figure and you'll quickly understand why
as we move along this video.
So until now we've been creating a bunch of icons that are basic shapes inside a figure and one drawback
from that is if I hold down option and copy this over here and I decide to change the style of this
for example if I zoom in here and move this to be a little bit wider here it doesn't change anywhere
else.
So I have to go in and copy and paste this across to different frames.
Now if I want I can choose a lot of these icons here.
I'm going to name this too.
But an menu and I'll name this too.
But Insearch and now I can click on any of these elements and click on this create component.
And now if I go to my components panel you can see I have these two components here and I can reuse
these anywhere that I want.
And that's really handy so I can drag and drop this on any frames that I want.
And now if I click on this master component and I change anything that I want the color or anything
else it changes everywhere that I have those copied.
I'm going to undo this and or remove those and I'll show you a more powerful way of using components.
For example we have this five star rating system.
So what if we had a component that we can reuse and we can change this Five-Star has to be one and a
half stars two and a half stars or whatever.
So first thing I'm going to do is click and ungroup all of these.
And what I want is I want an unfilled star so I'm going to choose this star here and then I want a field
star so I'll choose this star and I'll overlay this and I want to move this up inside of my layers panel.
I want to move this just up above the other one.
So now we have a light gray star and then a red star and I'm going to just call this star hyphen unfilled
and then I'll call this one star HIF and field.
Now all aligned these are the last one that we have here.
I'm going to make sure this is clear up of the top here in the laser system.
So if I scroll up here let's bring this to the top of the home page and I'm going to align this and
remember this doesn't align too well.
Now it's on subpixel so I can still double click inside of here and just select these two shapes underneath
this and all align that to snap.
And then I will call this star hyphen half hyphen field.
So we have the three versions of the star that we're always going to need fully filled and filled and
a half filled so I can select these objects here.
And let's just move this up to make sure that their layers are close to each other.
And now that I've done this I have my naming scheme good.
In fact I have some capital letters.
I'm just going to change this to be all lowercase.
Just for uniformity it really doesn't matter.
But I'm going to click on these three layers now and I'll click Create component and I can call this
master component star.
So now if I copy this five times I'm going hold down option and copy this five different times.
These child components have layer overrides so I can click on any of these stars here and I can choose
to hide the Handfield icon and also the field icon right here.
So now we have this unfilled icon I can do the same thing here.
Hide these two layers.
Let's say this is two and a half stars.
So here I want to keep this half star field visible but I want to remove this Starfield underneath it
and we have two and a half stars.
Now I can delete these guys here.
These are just simple shapes and I have these five child components and now I can center these here
in the center of this art board and actually create a nother component here.
And the reason why I didn't include this master component inside of here is because you can't nest master
components inside of other components you have to use child components.
So you create one master component and then let's copy all of these and click Create component again
and I'm going to call this five stars.
So this is a new master component.
I'm going to zoom out and we can just place this master component outside of the frame here because
we don't want to show it inside of our design.
Now I can delete this five star system over here and copy this master component hold down option and
I'll copy this over here.
And now the really nice thing is this is the child component.
But I can still drill down inside of here and choose this star here in the middle.
I'm going to make this field and I can make this one here half field so we can change it very quickly.
But now if we go in here and decide to give this a little bit more spacing I can still click on each
of these objects and I can just nudge this around and you can see over to the right.
This is also being updated.
So I'm changing this one master component here and the spacing is applied over here.
If I ever want to change the color of this star here of the half star and the full star here I can just
select both of these components so I'll choose star half field and Starfield and all the side.
Maybe I want these to be yellow.
So as soon as I change that to be yellow or gold I can now zoom out and everything is changed here so
very easily and very quickly we created components within components and we can do the same thing with
these guys here.
So if I click and ungroup these shift command G and group or you can right click inside of different
areas here and just choose ungroup.
Now I want to create one component with all of these objects.
So all I have to do is bring these down here and just align them to the center of each other and I'm
going to name these after I ungroup them all the way I can comment and I'll move these out of the way
so I can see which one I'm remaining.
So this is the icon
timer and this is the icon heart
now we can grab all three of these and a line in the middle and the center.
And because we have all of these now we can choose to create component.
And let's just call these icons.
Now if we hold down option we can move this and if we clicked this arrow in the layers panel now we
can decide that we want to only show the timer here.
Hold down option and drag over here.
And here we want to show the heart.
Let's drag one more time.
And here we want to show the comment.
So now at any time with this master component you can resize this you can move this around here in the
components area and you can change the styling.
Replace them and it's a great way to organize your icons this way so that you can toggle on and off
within this layers panel.
Now we can see that we have this master component icons and we also have this master component which
is the star.
And we don't really want this inside of our frames because we're only using the child components here
so we can click on this page view and click new page.
And this is where I like to create a page called symbols.
And if I click back to PAGE ONE I can click and drag here and just right click and move this to symbols
here.
Now if I ever want to see where the master component is to edit this I can right click inside of here
and click go to master component and then jumps right to the symbol page and tells me here's where it
is and now if I click on this and I add a stroke for example and I know that looks really ugly but just
for demo purposes let's go back to the page one that we can see that that changed here as well.
So get it right quick go back to master component and hold down command.
I can go into this group and remove this stroke here.
We'll go back into Page 1 and we can see that that's updated.
So I would recommend storing your master components inside of the symbols.
Or you can name this components to match where they really are.
I actually named them symbols because I'm used to sketch map where the components have a different name
and that is symbols.
So now this is renamed to components.
We have all of these icons here set up as components.
These are set up as components and we can do the same thing here.
This could be one component or they could be two.
So we can click on here quick create component and we can name this shopping create this component
and preparation.
Now the last component we want to create is this hot button.
So I'm going to call this button heart and we'll click Create component here.
Now there are times that this heart is going to be filled or unfilled.
So now we've created a component.
I'm going to zoom into here and this is the master component.
But we can still click inside of here.
We can see that we have a button heart inside of this Master component.
I'm just going to name this heart outline and if I use command C and command B to paste this I'm going
to name this one heart field
and the only thing I'm going to change here if I double click on this icon.
You can see I have these two shapes that I merged.
I actually want to bake this in so if I click on this harp field here I'm going to go to object and
flatten selection and that will bake everything has one shape.
And now I can click inside of here add a white fill and even remove the stroke here.
So we have one field heart and one outlined heart.
And anywhere we have this heart saved we can always toggle that on and off using these layers.
This is also a basic shape so we want to delete this.
We can click on this master component here and again hold down option and copy this over here and it
creates a child component.
And again now we can change the layering inside of here.
We can change this to be filled if we want this to be unfilled.
And because it's the same component if you ever change the color or style in the master section it'll
also change here.
Now let's scroll down here and we'll see this preparation window here if I just squeeze this down a
little bit to give some room over here.
I actually want to have each preparation area I want to have an icon here that represents the steps.
So I'm going to zoom in a little bit and I'll show you how to create some nice components for this.
So the first thing I'm going to do is click Oh for this ellipse and I'll just create a 20 pixel by pixel
circle here.
And I actually want this color to be the same colors that unfilled star so I can come back over here.
I can double click inside of here and if I choose the star unfilled.
All right click and copy style.
I'll come down here right quick and paste the style so that looks good.
I'm going to add some text inside of this so this text is just going to say one.
And we're using rubato here you can use whatever form that you want.
I'm going to make this bold here and I'll create this to be read text and if I zoom inside of here now
I'm going to do this to be centered
and I'll just change the width of this and the height of this to match.
And I'm going to sit this texture right in the center of this circle.
So we have a one and I can group this and call this step number and then I want to hold down option
and copy this and I say this step is completed.
Well now we want to double click in here until we select this circle here or this the lips and let's
fill this color to be red and I'm going to remove this text and now I want to create a checkmark icon.
So very easily I can use this pen tool.
And I'll just click and create a checkmark something like this will be good and I want the stroke to
be two pixels.
And now I want to cap the ends.
I want them to be rounded.
I'm going to change the color here to be white.
Get a scrape a few times.
I accidentally created a new shape out here I'm going to delete.
OK so we have that check mark.
I'm going to just balance this center it here in a circle.
And sometimes because it's a little bit offset and you kind of have to eyeball it I'm going to hold
down shift and let's just align this horizontally.
So we have this step completed.
So now I'm going to drag this vector shape into this other step number group instead of naming this
step number.
We're going to do step complete case.
So now we have our step number and our step complete we can do the same thing where we align this here
to the top we're in select both of these and we're to create a component and we'll just call this icon
steps.
Now because this is a master component I'm going to hold down option and drag this down to create a
child component.
And then again I'm going to right click and move the master component to the page components and then
I can use all these child components möglich inside of here.
Remove step complete.
And now I just have the step number but one thing that's really nice is I can hold down option and copy
this a few times and I can still go inside here in this text and if I double click a few times I can
change the number here to 1 to 3 and watch this if we change this to step 22 we see that there's not
enough padding around here and we've already committed to our design here and it's going to take a lot
of work to go on here and change all the sizes here of the fonts to kind of help this padding to be
correct.
But because we created components we can still right click and jump to master component.
So we can see that the master component hasn't changed if we double click inside of here and we choose
this group.
We're going to move this away and you can still see where it says one.
So that text that we changed is just overridden in those trial components it's not going to change here
but just for this master component I'm going to hide this.
And now I can click on this font inside of the master component and I can choose to resize this to 12
and maybe Let's try 10 here.
So we resize this to 10.
I can jump back into my pages and you can see it fits a lot nicer.
Now we could have clicked inside of just this number inside of here if we wanted this text to be larger
than just this text would be smaller.
We can click inside of here and change this to even be 48 pixels for example.
That's way too large.
I'm going to choose 14 pixels and you can see that this change and none of these changed.
That's because if you change anything in a child component that's actually going to override that change.
And when you change the master component now if you change the size it'll change the size of all of
these.
But it won't change this because you've overridden that size.
If you want to ever change this back you can double click inside of this text area and you can go back
into this little button here this instance button and you can choose to reset all overwrites.
So right now we overrode the name so we typed in 22 and that's different in the master component.
We overrode the text we overrode the textile so we can choose to not reset the text but we can reset
that style.
And that brings it back down and we could reset the name if we wanted.
But I'm just going to leave that and I can see that these are sitting a little bit high to the circles
on the right click and go to master component again.
And if I double click on this text.
Let's just have this sit down just a little bit something like this.
Let's jump back into our pages and see if that looks better.
I think that looks a little bit better here.
So now going down the list I'm going to just change this to four and let's say that these steps are
complete here.
So I'm just going to mark this is complete and the first few steps we'll just say are complete here.
Little Linus here with the top of this text
and let's say it's all but the last is complete and these are a little bit too many steps.
So I know if you try to follow this recipe you're probably going to screw up because I'm going to delete
a bunch of mid text inside of here.
But this is just for visual representation.
And I don't want the art board to be that long so I'm just changing this just deleting the little bit
of these steps.
So let's just have you know three or four steps here.
So three of them are completed and this fourth one is not.
Now I want to make sure things are lined up correctly so I'm going to hold down option b c there's 31
pixels here.
I actually want to nudge this so there's only 20 pixels here then I want 10 pixels to be in between
here and I just want to hold down shift and nudge at once.
And now we have 10 pixels and then I want this side to be 20 pixels so I'm going to hold down command
and nudge this one two three four five six.
OK.
So everything looks good.
And we have our steps.
Now zoom out here and take a look at this.
This is all looking really good now.
And to match the lining here this shows 14 by 14.
I'm just going to line this here with the edge here and then nudge this holding now command left arrow
left arrow and command shift left arrow once more.
So we have a 20 by 20 so we can see this is a line really good.
And go into a line.
The ease with the edges here.
So those are components we've now converted all of our icons to components here and they're ready to
be reused throughout all of the other designs.
For example I'm just going to hold down option here and I'll just move this over here because I know
we're going to use the same kind of five star scheme inside of this design in the future.
Again now if we click on this components panel you can see all of our components here.
We have six components on our home page and we have three components here under the components background.