In most cases nowadays we're designing for multiple device screens.
And this starts to become a challenge translating how the paddings and margins and layout will look
to the developers as they're developing these screens for the different device sizes.
Well Fishman has a really nice tool to help this become much easier to export multiple screen sizes
and not having to design for multiple screens but using constraints so you can stretch this frame and
see exactly what it's going to look like at that size.
And you'll notice when I stretch this right now things look a little bit broken and they're not exactly
resizing the right way or the way that you would intend.
So I'm going to click command Z and that's what we're going to do as we're going to set up this frame
here to be responsive.
We're going to set up a constraints for all of these elements.
Now before we do that I'm going to just zoom into these two art boards here and I want to just hold
down option and copy some elements over here to kind of complete this design and move this down here
and I have this centered.
And if we were really focusing on this design I would get the padding exactly right and the spacing.
But just to save some time I'm just going to eyeball this and we can work on that a little bit later.
Now I'm going to add just a few more elements here.
I'm going to hold down option and copy this up here to be aligned with the center of these icons.
I'm going to call this popular recipes and make this the same red color here and go down once more.
We call this entrees over here.
Appetisers hold down option once more and call this dessert.
And I want these to be subtle gray here and will probably make this thirteen point and regular
and because this is the one that is selected right now I'm going to make this black and medium and using
the L key I'm going to draw a line just below this and let's make this two pixels and let's cap off
the ends with a rounded.
And here I'm just going to give this going to center this command g to group it and center it with the
board and then all ungroup here.
Shift command G and I'll give these 30 pixels in between each mesh just nudging the U.S. holding down
the shift and the arrow keys.
So now if I hold down option you can see that there's 30 pixels in between.
And we can easily see the entrées are selected as change in the sizing and the padding here.
It really doesn't matter too much you can move this around however you want.
And I think the last thing I want to do is hold down command G and center this with the board shift
command to ungroup.
So now we have this design near completed and we want to make this responsive.
So the first thing we do is test this out.
We can see that things are broken here.
So going down one by one let's just fix this top area right here.
So we know we want this icon to be constrained to the top left of this frame.
So now when we try this we can see that's exactly what we want it to do here.
We're going to hit command Z to resize this back to where it was.
And now this popular recipes we want to center this with the frame and instead of the left top we want
this to just be centered and we want it to sit at the top and sitting at the top means if I scale this
down it's just going to stay there.
If I change this to sit at the center what is going to do is center this where it's at here between
the top and the bottom.
So change back to top center.
And then this guy right here is going to be right top.
So now we have our Hetter area behave exactly how it should.
And now we have to deal with these guys.
So if I want to apply a constraint to everything I can select all of these layers and click command
G or control G on the windows and I'm going to name this categories.
And now I want this also to be centered and sit at the top.
So now we have this group as centered.
And we can resize this and we can see that it is centering each element on the artwork but that's not
exactly what we want.
It's centering relative to this frame.
But if you want to create a new frame around this we chose to group this and we named this group category.
But let's convert this group to its own frame.
And this is what we call a frame within a frame so that we can set the constraints only within this
frame and is independent of what we said in this frame.
So I'm going to click on this group and you can see that it's a group here but I can change this to
a frame instantly by clicking on frame right here.
And so now this has its own frame.
And these objects are going to be centered within this frame itself not within this frame.
So now we have a left top constraint here.
We're going to center this frame for the top and center.
And now when we stretch this we can see that's precisely what we want to have happen there.
Command Z and now we're working our way up to these images here.
So I can group these items command G because they want these to stay within each other and I want this
to be center top when we can see that that behaves correctly.
And now let's move these images inside of that same group.
So we have this group up here.
I'm going to select both of these with Option Command and right bracket I'm going to move these to the
top near this other one.
So now we have these two mass groups and this group I'm going to move to the top as well.
And holding down command and selecting both of these I mean just to move them inside of this group here.
So now we have all of these grouped.
And same thing center top
and again we have to convert this into its own frame.
So now that's working correctly.
And we have this component works the same way as a frame where we can just choose to create this at
the top center and it's not going to stretch like a group does.
Now I can resize this that always stays centered on the same thing over here so you can select multiple
things at once if you know they're going to have the same alignment properties and just going to make
sure that this is already centered on the board.
Here we go.
And again the center top and these are the last things here.
So first of all just making sure that it has the right spacing that you want initially
that's probably pretty good.
Move these down just a tiny bit.
And now I can select all of these commands read a group change this group into a frame and let's center
this last thing.
But this text we actually want this to be pinned to the left and right.
So we wanted to always be 20 pixels on the left 20 pixels on the right and same thing here.
We can actually stretch this here depending on if the text increases or decreases.
We still want to have 20 pixels on the left and right.
So we're going to choose left and right here and now check this out.
This is for the iPhone 8.
If you want to look at the eight plus we can look at that very easily.
Look at the iPhone 5 s or if we have the galaxy note or whatever we can change the size and very easily
your developers can see exactly what you intend this to look like during development for multiple screen
sizes.
You can also change the width here so 375 and you have the option here because it's turned into a frame.
I can decide I want to see what it looks like on the Galaxy S8 that changes proportionately.
And the same thing I can choose maybe a 7 inch tablet What does that look like here.
So you can see that you have that nice web for the 7 inch tablet.
We're going to change this back to the iPhone 8.
So once you get the hang of setting up constraints it's just a matter of testing things once you set
them up making sure that things are flowing correctly and once you really do get the hang of this it
takes probably two minutes to convert something like this into a responsive design.
So before we move into the next video I would like you to go through this our board here.
This may be a little bit simpler to set some things like this up.
I'm going to just Center this but just go through here and just set the constraints here for this frame.
And again you can always test it out by just stretching things you can already see that some things
are broken like this image here.
So if I hit undo this image would just be pinned left to right or left and right.
And we can see that.
Now that's fixed.
So just go through and change some of those things on your own and see if you can get this to behave
and perform the way that you'd like.