Let's begin adding in combining shapes to our design here and we'll start off with this splash screen.
So if you just hold down Z and draw a rectangle you can zoom into the splash screen and the first thing
I want to do inside of this black frame is draw a rectangle that's the same size as the frame here.
And the reason why I want to do this is to change the fill color to this default red.
But I also want to display an image inside of this shape.
So I can click on this feel again and I can feel this shape with an image and here it's going to ask
me to choose the image and under the assets folder you can choose any of these images that you'd like.
I'm going to choose this entree lasagna J peck here so I can click open and you can see that that's
now the background of this frame.
But I want to move this image field down below this color fill.
Now I want to change the opacity of this red field to 90 percent.
And I actually want to hide the layout grid here to make this little bit easier to see.
And so we have our first shape it's this rectangle here if we click and drag you can see this rectangle
snaps to the frame edges and with rectangles or other shapes you can click on these radius anchors to
expand or decrease the radius of this shape.
And if you want to manipulate the individual radiuses of this shape you can hold down option and drag
and that will only drag the radius in and out.
Just for that one corner we're going to leave those the same here.
And now let's create a chef's hat icon so we can do this by using a few ellipses.
So I'll just draw some.
I'll hold down shift so I can constrain the width and the height and let's just drag this out something
like this and I'll hold down shift to select all of these guys and make sure everything is distributed
correctly.
And I'm just going to zoom in just a little bit more here and this is going to take some playing around
with so maybe I will select the circle and if you hold down shift in the up arrow key it will nudge
this about 10 pixels each time that you hit the arrow key.
So I've just nudged this up 20 pixels.
I've got a nice shape here and now I'll draw a rectangle here.
For the bottom area of the hat I'm going to move this around just a little bit.
And now if I want I can click hold down shift and select these three circles which is going to group
these for now so that when I hold down shift and select this rectangle I can align everything to the
center.
Make sure everything's aligned really good and I'll just hold down shift command g to ungroup everything
now so we can see these shapes.
We have three circles and one rectangle and that's making up our chef's hat.
Now with this chef's hat I actually want the corners here to have a radius so I can do that by clicking
on this radius.
Anchor and change in that I think 7 pixels looks good.
And we have the starting of our chefs hat already.
So all we need to do at this point is select all of these shapes by holding down shift three simple
shapes and we can come up here and we can see some settings for joining some shapes together for subtracting
them and you can play around with these to create some nice combination effects for simple shapes.
So I'm just going to use the union selection and now we have a one simple shape.
I can change the fill color of this shape if I wanted or I could even remove the feel of this shape
and add a stroke and the stroke.
Let's make this white and let's say I want this to be 10 pixels.
So we have this acting as one shape here but I can still double quick to drill down into this and you
can see that it is actually behaving as four different shapes that are joined together so I can still
tweak this a little bit and give it a little bit more personality if I wanted make these a tiny bit
on even
which is very handy to make some subtle changes there.
The last thing I'm going to do for this shape so click in the shapes tool and create a line and I'm
just going to click and drag holding down shift and I want to copy the same style so I'm going to write
click here and copy style and I'll right click on this image.
And paste this style.
So we have a nice pasted style but I want the ends of this line to be rounded so I can jump into the
advanced menu of The Strokes and decide that I want the cap to be rounded.
I've got a nice rounded effect and now I'm just going to select this line.
Hold down option and just drag down to get just one more line below that.
And now I want to join all of this as one shape.
So I'm going to hold down Shift while I'm selecting these two lines and this one shape.
And now that I have these three selected I can hit command G.
And that will all be grouped into one shape.
Now please scroll down and move over into the home frame.
There are a few other icons that we can recreate with basic shapes here as well.
So I'll just zoom into the top area here for some navigation icons and we want to search icon here on
the home page and also a menu icon.
So the menu icon can be very simple.
I can go back into the shapes tool and click on rectangle and here I'm just going to quickly draw a
hamburger menu.
So going to hold down option here and copy this leave in six pixels in between and we can see that this
shape is 41 pixels by six pixels.
Now I just make this an even 40 by selecting all of these rectangles and choosing 40 pixels in the design
panel and then I want us to have a little bit more personality so I'm going to just decrease the size
of these a little bit.
To make their menu icon look a little bit staggered.
And the last thing I want to do here is I actually want bees radiuses here on the right side to be curved.
So zooming in here I want to do that and curve these edges what I can do is select all three of these
rectangles and I can change the radius here if I change this to 3 pixels so you can see that everything
changes to three pixels.
But what if I want to individually change the pixel sizes on each corner.
Well I'm going to undo this and here this gives me control to change the radius for each corner starting
with the top left.
So the top left we know we want to be zero and the top right.
We want to be three pixels and the bottom right.
We want to be three pixels and then we want the bottom left to stay zero pixels.
So we have our hamburger menu here and we can group this as well by just selecting everything and choosing
Union selection.
And now we have this one icon here I can change all of it to be black red whatever color that I want
here.
So now we want to create a magnifying glass and we can do that by going into the shape's options here.
I'm going to click on the elipse tool and holding down shift or just drag and draw an ellipse and we'll
start out with 23 pixels I think that's good.
And we can actually remove the fill here by selecting on the outside of this row clicking the subtract
and then we'll add a stroke.
And we want the stroke to be red.
And I think inside the stroke is good we can align this to the outside of the middle or the inside we're
going to keep it on the inside.
And I'm going to have the stroke wait be two pixels here.
Now I'm going to draw a rectangle.
And now four pixels is good maybe four pixels by 10 or 12 and we can change this later if we want.
And the feel of this brunette changed to be the same red color and I'm just going to slit both of these
and align them.
So we have two simple shapes here and you'll notice when I tried to align this this has 23 pixels but
this has four pixels so we have an even with an odd with which is making it look a little bit staggered
sort of change that.
I'm just going to change the width of this to 20 pixels.
So they're both even all do in a line again.
And that's just nudge this up with our arrow keys.
Now one thing that you can do with rectangles or circles or any other shape.
If I zoom in here I can select this rectangle and if I hold down command with my arrow keys I can nudge
up or down and it will decrease or increase the size whether that's the height or if I use the right
or left arrows it's the width.
So it's a very nice shortcut to nudge the sizes to get it precisely the way that you want.
Now I'm going to add just a small radius here of one pixel around we have a nice rounded corners on
this magnifying glass and the last thing we can do is select this fill in this stroke and choose union
selection and actually combines this stroke with the fill which makes it quite nice.
Now by double click inside of here.
Hold down shift to select this circle.
I'm just going to rotate the both of these at 45 degrees and hit return.
And now we have this shape the shape shows twenty five point eight five pixels and we want it to be
an even 40 pixels so I can click here to constrain the proportions and choose this to be 40 pixels.
And now if I hold down command and zoom out with my scroll will you can see that that's proportionally
the same width as this hamburger menu.
So I'm going to bring this over here and we have a nice starting out of a hamburger menu and a magnifying
glass menu with some basic simple shapes.
Now in the same home page we can tap our for rectangle and if I hold down the ship I can strain the
size of this.
We want this rectangle to be 2:21 by 2:21 So we'll just match it with the columns here.
And this is going to be where image is going to live.
But to the top right of this image we're going to have a heart icon.
So I'm going to just zoom in here and to draw a heart.
I'm going to click and drag a.
I'll start out with 10 pixel by 15 pixel here.
And I'll make this white so you can see it.
And the first thing we can do is change the radius of this heart is going to be one side of the heart
here.
So the top left is going to be five pixels the top right is going to be five pixels.
And then these two at the bottom are going to be zero pixels now I can hold down option and copy the
shape I'm going to rotate this 90 degrees holding down shift.
Not going to line this here.
You can see we have a nice heart.
So now I will select both of these shapes.
Rotate this forty five degrees for our heart shape.
And the last thing we want to do is hit this Join button and now we have a heart icon.
And I want to change the feel of this to be removed.
I'm going to add a stroke and this will be a white stroke.
And let's try to pixels here.
Now if I hold down command and zoom out you can see what that looks like and how this sits in relation
to this image that we're going to have so I can set this to that top right here.
And then instead of using my x and y values here to nudge this around I can hold down shift and just
nudge this left 10 pixels and down 10 pixels and it's sitting nicely now inside of this image.
If you ever want to see the sizing or the relationship of sizing between two devices you can select
this heart for example and then just hold down option and you'll get these nice red indicators of how
many pixels are between the edges of certain elements and you can see here because the shape is on some
pixels.
This notched nine point nine three pixels if you want to change that to be an even width you can lock
proportions here.
And let's just change this to maybe be 20 pixels wide.
You can change that.
And now let's try this again solemnised at the top right.
Hold down shift and left and down arrow.
Now one last thing you might notice when we increase the size here that doesn't increase the radius.
What we should have done if we undo this a little bit is go to the scale tool and now using the scale
tool you can scale this up and down and the radius will also scale with it the way that we did it before
is to actually use the Move tool and tried scaling this which resizes.
But you can see those radiuses still stay about five pixels if you ever did accidently resize it this
way.
And we can see that those radiuses haven't scaled.
You can always double click inside of here.
Hold down shift and then just make a quick change maybe.
So these 10 pixels now and you can see a nice rounded radius.
So it's really nice to show you how to troubleshoot these things too because it'll always come up as
your scale on things you might wonder why the radiuses or the strokes aren't looking good.
So there's a big difference between just resizing and using that scale tool.
So now we know we want a five star rating system for our recipe.
And under the shape's options we have the star tool that's really handy.
So I'm going to just click and drag and hold down shift to lock my ratio and I can drag this any size
that I want.
And later I can come in here lock my proportions.
I'm just going to make the 16 pixels wide here and let's zoom in so I can either keep this style that
is given me.
But I have a few controls to change the style to how I want this to look.
And one of those is changing the counts here I can change this to three four five or 30 count and I
can also change the ratios to if I want to give these points a little bit more bolder I can do that
with this ratio anchor and that I have a radius control and I'll just zoom in here a little bit to show
you how this radius control works.
So if I push this down you can see I have an option for one or two pixel radius and so that seems like
a bit much.
So if you want something that's more subtle than that you can still go into this design panel and I'll
just type Point 2 ratio just for a nice soft point here unless the I want to change this field to be
a little bit lighter because this is the background to the star and I'm going to zoom out and holding
down option.
I'll just copy this four times.
And we know with this particular recipe is going to be four and a half stars so I'm going to select
four of these stars make them red.
But how do we get half of this star to be red.
Well if you hold down option and copy this we've seen that we can combine shapes but we can also subtract
shapes.
So we have this star and we want to subtract a rectangle from the star.
So I'm just going to drag a rectangle here we're going to snap it to the very center of this star and
I'm going to turn down the opacity here just to show you what's happening.
So we have this rectangle that's overlain this star.
And so now when I select these two simple shapes I can go in here and I can still use this union selection.
But that just gives me one really weird shape.
Or I can click in this down arrow and you subtract selection to subtract the rectangle from the star
which gives me a nice half star.
If you'd like to see what the other options do you can play around with that by just clicking undo.
And we'll go and use exclude selection which will exclude anything that's intersecting between the two
selections.
And we also have intersect.
So anything that's the intersecting it will give us that right half of the star.
So there's multiple ways that we can join or subtract shapes together.
I'm just going to stick with this subtract selection here.
And now I want to copy this style and paste the style on this star and we see very easily we have this
nice four and a half stars.
Now you can see here the star isn't quite a line and that's because instead of being a nice even 16
by 16 pixels now will be cut it in half.
It has a 7.3 by thirteen point eighty five pixels in here.
So if we want to align this we can still get past this by double clicking inside of here and we'll just
select both of these shapes inside of this join.
And once we click both of the shapes we can snap this to align with other shapes.
It's just a weird quirk but learning how to get past things like this will really help you save time
and align things.
Now zoom out here to see the finished result.
And we can select all of these shapes and use command g to group all of them and just make sure they're
centered here on the frame.
Now these are just a few ways that we can use shapes you see that we created a nice icon here hamburger
menu search icon and this hurt here learning how to use the shapes tools and also the bully on tools
that we see here.
Give you a lot of power in creating the icons that you'd like.