If you're following along from the previous video Feel free to use the same file as we continue designing.
If you're just starting with this video you can open up the drawing icons using the pen tool thick file.
So now we're going to show you how to create icons using the pen tool and we'll do this under the recipe
details frame.
So before we do that I'm just going to hold down option and copy some of these items here and this heart.
We're also going to reuse this over here on the top right.
So I'm going to nudge this over.
Make it 10 pixels.
By 10 pixels by using the arrow key and shift to nudge this over.
So we have a nice starting and now there are two icons down below here that we want to create.
So I'm going to zoom into this area and if I click on this recipe details frame I'm going to just hide
this layout grid for now as we design these icons.
So these icons that we create are going to live inside of a circle and these circles are each going
to be 36 pixels.
So we'll just create a 36 pixel circle.
We'll fill this with red.
And let's zoom in and let's create our first icon inside of here so we can use this pen tool and this
pen tool we can just click certain areas to create straight lines and if we want to close the shape
we just click on this last note here and I'll close the shape for us.
So it's very simple to create straight shaped objects.
And if I hit escape it will get me out of edit mode and I can delete this.
But there are also times where we want to click and drag to create a curve.
So I'll show you how this works here.
That's create a shopping bag.
We'll do that by clicking the pen tool.
And I'm just going to click and drag certain areas here
and we have a bag shape and I can click on this anchor here and just nudge this to make things even
click this one and that looks good.
So now that I've done that I also want to create a handle here so I can click and here I'll just click
and drag and it'll introduce us to some drag handles here.
You can see here this drag handle is pushing this curve to the left.
This is pushing out to the right.
And now I can click in and this and if we ever want to change that we can use this select tool right
here select this note.
You can see these drag handles and we can move these and change each one.
You can see how these are locked with the left and right handle.
If I hold down option it'll break that length here so that I can drag this independently of the other
one
so we can easily move these drag handles around and get the shape exactly how we want it.
And once we're done using the pen tool we've created a nice shopping bag I can now because I use strokes
using the pen tool if I decided to add a field to this it wouldn't look very good because you don't
want the field to be where the handle area is.
So I'm going to hit command Z or controls the on the windows and I can still double click inside of
here and using this paint bucket tool I can decide I want this area to be filled and not this area.
So now that area is filled I'm going to make this film Black and I will hit done here and we have our
shopping bag.
Last thing we need to do is put it inside of the circle and it looks a little bit too big inside of
the circle someone going to constrain the proportions.
And I'll just make this 16 pixels here.
And that looks like a nice size.
And now I want to make everything white so I'm going to change this field to be white.
I'll change the stroke to be white.
And the last thing I want to do is double click instead of here.
I can still select these notes that I used in the pen tool a hold down shift to select just the four
corners here and I'm going to add just a one pixel radius to make those corners curved inside of there.
Now if we hold down option and we copy this circle there's one more icon we're going to create with
the pen tool.
And that's the chef's icon has the same icon that we created on the splash screen.
But I just want to show you how to create this using the pen tool.
So I like to create it outside of this box.
First of all we can fit it in later.
So I'm just going to create the bottom of the hat here.
Do something like this.
And then we can just play around with these kind of Bolger's on the chef's hat.
And right here you can see that I have a left drag handle on a right drag handle so if I let go and
I want a shape to come around here now I actually can't do that unless I hold down option and select
this to break the symmetry between these drag handles so I can say I want this curve to start out here
and you can see it's giving me a little preview of what's that's going to look like.
So here I can say I'll start here.
And let's just click and drag will hold down option to break that symmetry again and let's click and
drag somewhere here and here.
So you can see this is looking a little bit funky but that's one really nice feature with this pen tool
as we can click on this new tool inside of our edit mode and very easily we can just adjust these and
make the curves really nice and maybe this.
We want to move over here.
And so within just a few seconds we can kind of clean up those curves here
and it really doesn't matter if it has a huge amount of symmetry because this looks more organic if
you just played around with different shapes here.
Move this down here.
Bring this down starting to look pretty good.
This looks a little bit flat will decrease these a little bit.
And then we want to select just these two notes at the bottom at a two pixel radius bring the same
something like that looks decent.
So we have our chef's hat and by double click on this again to jump into edit mode.
I'm just going to use the pen tool to create two more lines here could escape to and that and one more
right here and again hit escape will double click to end it.
And we also want to jump into the advanced menus and cap this as rounded for these edges here and we
can now resize this to whatever size that we want and fit this side up here will make the stroke quite.
And now if you want to double click inside of this to go into attack mode again the last thing we want
to do is use this paint bucket tool to feel the inside of this with the color white.
So now zooming out we have a shopping icon and a preparation icon so as movies down here.