If you want to design more freeform shapes you can use the pencil tool and you can find this tool here
under this drop down arrow next to the pen tool.
You'll find this pencil tool.
I'm just going to hold down Z and draw a rectangle here to just zoom into this area.
So if you do have a Wakem tablet or something.
I'm just using my mouse right now.
So this text might be a little bit choppy but you can kind of see how the pencil tool works here.
If we just
create some freeform cursive for each
and the nice thing about this is although the text is quite choppy you can still jump into the move
tool in here and double click on the shape you have access to all of these nodes so I can select all
of these for example and use this Bantul and it will try to help it become a little bit more curvy or
I can select some of these notes here go under the vector menu and delete and he'll selection and it
will make that a lot more curvy.
I'm going to do the same thing over here.
Vector Dilley and hill so you can see how much cleaner your shapes can be if you just spend a little
bit of time after you start out a little bit rough.
So like this one for example Lee Hill just makes that nice and curvy.
Same thing here to Lee Hill
and then from here you can still change things around.
So it's a very nice combination to use that.
Now if you want to use the pencil tool for tracing as well then you can import images into your thick
file and then use the pencil tool to closely trace certain shapes.
Now because I was using my mouse this wasn't a great example of how to use the pencil tool there is
something that I love using with this pencil tool.
When I'm on my Mac and that is the app called Astro pad and my iPad.
So using my iPad I can use of the same way as a Wakem tablet or if you have a Wakem tablet with a pencil
you can do the same kind of thing and you have more control over the look of this pencil shape.
So here very easily I can just start creating some letters
and easily here and do things don't make it the first round.
And here you can see that this first pass looks a lot cleaner.
So you can still use those vector menus to heal selections to smooth joints some selections and to clean
this up even further.
But from here I can easily choose the shapes and align them the way that I want.
Resize them the way that I want and get this look exactly how I want it.
Last thing I'm going to do here is change the stroke to white.
And let's just add a three pixel feel here and just a line this little bit better
something like that will work good.
And if you don't want all of these layers here to mess up your layers panel just hit command G and everything
will be selected here.
Now we have a nice handmade font.