To show you how text and the text properties work are going to be adding some text into the recipe details
frame that we created in a previous video.
If you haven't followed along and just jumped into this video then you can find this file under the
Chapter 4 folder in your exercise files.
So to save time typing up some text I have a recipe prime rib text file you can find in the assets folder.
And here let's just open this up and we can just refer to this as we crank along here.
So the first thing we want to do is copy this text prime rib roast and that's just click on this tee
tool here.
I'm just going to click in a general area and paste this in prime rib roast.
Now we can jump back into our text edit folder that's copy the summary text here command see or control
see on Windows and next time we use the tiki we're going to click and drag for a certain box that we
want to surround this text with.
And I can hit command V here and paste this text inside of here.
And we can already see that this page is going to be quite a bit longer than the others.
So I'm going to drag this down here and next up pull this down.
I can copy some of this text by holding down an option.
I'm just going to copy this down here.
Copy this down here and this.
I'm just going to call this shopping list.
And I have this in all caps and here I'm going just going to put this lower case preparation.
I'm going to show you why I do that later.
Next let's copy this over holding down an option we can drag and let's jump back into our text file
here and I'll copy this paste it in here.
Hold down option
and copy this and paste it in so you can really type in anything that you want here.
This is just some sample text to help you understand how the text properties works.
So we have some one liner text here that's pretty simple if we click in here if we want to make this
bold For example we can choose bold.
We can change the size to say 18 pixels here.
And we can change the center justification here very easily and just Center this with this icon here.
Now I can already see I want this text to be the same as this one.
So what I can do here is I can right click and copy this style and paste the style directly into here
and I have the same center justification eighteen point bold.
Here I can center that as well.
And now what do we do about these ingredients and the preparation.
Well the first thing I want to do is just change this maybe fourteen point here and you can see this
text is going beyond this bounding box here.
So I can click and drag this to surround this or I can click on this advanced menu and choose to auto
resize the height based off of the contents in there.
So now if I jump in here and I continue typing that bounding box is going to resize the next thing I
can do here is add a paragraph or line spacing.
So this is your regular line high.
And this is your paragraph spacings so I want to play with this little bit I'm just going to add 10
here.
So I really like how this is turning out here I can do the same thing in copy style and paste style
here and that's looking really good.
But notice here we already have some paragraphs here that were entered in the text so we can go through
and delete this to keep it accurate as far as the spacing goes.
And here we have the same problem with the bounding box so we can go into the advanced menu where you
can resize the height here and it looks like we need to resize our frame to be higher as well so I'm
going to hold down command.
Zoom out.
And I can resize that.
Let's just zoom back in here make sure our looks good.
I actually want to increase the line height here to be maybe 110 percent.
Just to give a tiny bit more spacing.
Now I can select these different elements and just position them
got 20 pixels here.
I'll probably put maybe 50 pixels one two three four five 50 pixels in between these two.
And same thing here.
One two three four or five and we've got 50 pixels so we already added some text.
Got a really nice sizing here.
I'm just going to use Option Command C as a shortcut to copy the style An Option Command V to paste
this in the prime rib roast.
So we've got that styling down here and now I want to show you why I didn't capitalize this but I did
capitalize this so if you type things in caps it's hard to have control over changing the capitalization
later.
But if you have this all lowercase here I can quickly go into a bunch of text in my design file and
I can go and choose to transform this text to all uppercase here.
So you have a lot more flexibility and what that font is going to look like is you design further out.
And lastly I'm going to copy the style here and paste it right here.
And I think that's looking really good.
Now I've already formatted all this text and rather than use the copy style paste style a bunch of times
I might find out that later I want this text to not be completely black but I want it to be a little
bit lighter.
So rather than clicking and trying to select everything in our art board we can click on one of these
go under Edit and we can choose to select everything with the same style here so selecting all of these
three and I can quickly go in here and say now the style I want the text to be just a tiny bit lighter.
So something like this and you can see that it changed that for these two.
But this right here has something different.
There's something different in the style and that's the line spacing here.
So Option Command see Option Command B and we have that same type of styling.
What's really great though is you don't have to rely on one style for this entire text box field.
So for example as far as the amount of ingredients that we have here I want this to be bold and I want
that to be totally black.
So once I change that you can definitely see the difference between the amount and the actual ingredient.
So I can do the same thing here.
This black and bold
and we can change that independent of the other characters in this bounding box.