A recipe design it's finally starting to come to life.
And to help this along let's add some images here in the homescreen and the recipe Detail Screen to
find the images we want to import here.
Let's go to the shape tools and go to place image.
And here we can find our assets folder and inside the assets folder there are a few entrée images.
So the first one I'm going to import is this prime rib a j peg.
So I can click open here and now if I hover over any of these boxes I can place this inside of that
boxed area.
So I want to place it right here.
But I also want to place that same image right here.
So set of going into the shapes tools again and going to place image I can right click on this and go
to copy style.
Right click on this area and paste style.
And the reason why that works is because this is a feel style where the image was placed as a fill.
Now there may be times you want to adjust the image within this square.
For example if I click on this square here you can see how things resize and it kind of fits to feel.
But if I double click inside of here what I want to have happen is I want to move this image actually
inside of this rectangle.
Well I can't do that because this is an image feel and not an image mask.
But there are a number of ways I can get around this.
So if I move this over here and this is 220 pixels Let's put 220 pixels tall and I can go to my rectangle
tool.
I'm going to create a rectangle again here that's 220 pixels and all fine tune this here to 20.
And just snap this to the edge here.
So I've recreated this and if I hold down option command and the left bracket here I can move this clear
down in the léa schemes.
That's just a quick shortcut option command right bracket to bring to the top or left bracket to bring
it to the bottom.
That's the same as just dragging this around.
Now I can click on this image and if I click on this hold down shift and click on the image behind it
I can use this use as mask option here.
And what that does is it sets this back rectangle here as just a mask.
And so I can still click on this image and I can drag it around.
I can resize it and manually place this exactly how I want it inside of this area.
It's maybe nice if you place in the image and things are cropped out that you want to appear in the
image you want to slide something down or place it just right.
You can do it this way.
But there's also another option.
So I'm going to hit command z a few times and just to get rid of this rectangle here.
And now we're back to just this image again if I double quick I can't really move this around within
the cropped area but a quicker way of doing this is actually going into this image menu here.
And choosing crop and now that I have crop enabled I can still click on this image here and maneuver
it and even resize this.
So those are just two ways of masking the image either using a crop or masking that image with another
shape.
For the most part you're probably just going to want to go in here and choose Krok but some areas where
you may want to use the mask for example is if you have a circle.
And I'm just going to tap the O keyboard shortcut and draw a circle right here and I'm going to hold
down option and copy this image and with Option Command right bracket I can bring this to the top.
So things like this you can't use that crop setting.
So I can still shift click to select this circle with this image and if I click on use as mask.
Now I have things masked within this circle or this shape.
So there are multiple ways to do this and some have better results than others in the application that
you're using it.
So I would just keep that in mind while you're using the crop or just the use as a mask feature.
Lastly we have two other images here that we need to import.
So I'm just going to go to my assets folder here and we'll import these two entry images.
And you notice when I just drag them in from the Finder window then they show up is really large.
So I can just resize this down and I can just shift select this image here use as mask.
New this around how I want it to look and notice when I drag this image out side of the frame.
It kind of places this in the background so it need to be a little bit careful of that.
Let's move this up here.
And same thing here I'm going to resize this little bit in porches rather really large OK.
And we'll slip these two and use as mask
and
bring this over here.
And you can see this one outside of the frame so I can just command X quick on the frame command.
Make sure it's pasted back in the frame here.
Now that we have these images all mask the last thing to do is add a drop shadow and a corner radius.
So here I'm just going to have a radius of five pixels and we'll do the same thing on these images here
five pixels
and less quick on effects drop shadow.
And we're going to just turn this down to maybe two pixels here and then here we're going to add another
drop shadow
and we'll add one more drop shuttle so we're adding to drop shadows here one of them is a really sharp
drop shadow one and this one I want maybe 10 pixels in a Blair to be 20 pixels something like this and
the shading to be 10 percent.
So now we have all of our image masked.
We have some nice shadow effects on those massive images.
And everything's looking good.