In a previous video we created these icons like this hamburger menu and this spotlight here and even
these stars but creating each little icon can sometimes be really cumbersome and there are thousands
of libraries out there that we can use inside of our design to get a design out quickly.
You may also have some icons inside of Adobe Illustrator or some images that you find on Google or other
online resources and those formats are very easy to drag and drop.
So I want to show you a few ways that you can import some icons in here and to do that let's get started
zooming into this home screen here.
And now if we go into our assets folder we see that we have an icon here.
Now we have this icon in three different formats.
We have Adobe Illustrator P.N. G and S Ficci.
Now unfortunately right now if I try to drag and drop this Adobe Illustrator file in here you can see
that this failed to import so thick that doesn't recognize the Adobe Illustrator file completely.
But if I double click and open this Adobe Illustrator file you can see this common vector graphic and
we can actually click commands see we can go into Sigma and click command.
And this pace the SPG directly inside of Sigma.
And this actually paste this is a group.
And if we drill down we can see that this is actually a vector image.
So the first thing we do when we import is just hold down shift command g a few times.
And now we have this vector graphic all vectorized If we zoom in here we can still double click and
edit this graphic exactly how we would if we created this inside of Sigma.
Another way that we can import this graphic is through a pian g This is a portable networked graphic
it's almost the same as an image.
And we can see when we import this in it's a raster graphic meaning it's calculating the pixels here
and behaves like an image instead of a vector graphic.
The downside to something like this is you don't have the same editing capabilities as something like
SPG or Adobe Illustrator files where you can edit these and manipulate the files themselves with the
image because this icon has an image.
If we click inside of this area we have some image editing controls which doesn't work too well with
just a black icon and there are some ways to get around maybe the color of this so we can still go onto
this image and add a field for example and I can click inside of this and choose a solid fill say I
want to choose the same red icon here.
So I change it to red to what that did was it overlaid a red fill over top of the entire rectangle that
this image is inside.
I can hack my way into incorporating this red inside of this image by clicking on some of these overlay
controls.
And you can see that I have Darkon multiply color burn and if I choose something like light in what
that will do is apply this red on any dark elements so I can still change the color.
Now change this to any color that I want but I have very basic editing controls.
And now if I hold down a command and zoom out you can see it still looks really decent as it's smaller.
But if I want to use this is any larger size here I'm going to get that pixelation for the most part
you're going to want to add to all of your icons in SVGA and find Ficci files.
And that brings us to our last file format.
This is Fiji.
So if you're in a program like Adobe Illustrator you can export any of your icons or graphics into FICCI
and that behaves the same way as copying and pasting.
So I still have this where I can change this color to red and I can double click inside of here and
I have the same editing controls and it's very handy.
So I'm going to delete these and I'll use this little comment icon.
And we want to have two other icons.
You want a heart and a timer.
So in order to get those icons there's a tool that's really handy.
And this is a tool I use all the time.
If you go to Icahn's 8 dot com you can search for any kind of icon here so I'll just search for heart
and you can see how many versions of the heart icon that we have.
And same thing with a timer.
So I'll just type in timer here and hit return.
And I have multiple timers now Icahn's 8 is free it's free to download these icons as a P and G and
remember that PMG is not very editable.
So if you want SVGA access there's a paid version and if you click see pricing here you can see that
it's $20 a month.
And it gives you access to hundreds of thousands of graphics whether you get the free version or the
paid version.
They do have a desktop app and this app is actually right here.
This ikons 8 menu bar.
So if I click on that you can see this pulls up right inside of my Mac and if you have the free version
again you only have this PLG option where you can drag and drop pian GS inside of here.
But because I have a paid version SVGA I can quickly search for icons like heart and I can find something
like this.
I think that looks good.
And I want to find a timer.
I can just type timer and I like this one.
It was going to drag and drop this inside and you can see the difference between this pian Geographic
and this SPG last thing I'm going to select these two and just hold down shift command Jeeta ungroup
this a few times.
And now I want the height of all of these to be the same.
So I'm going to lock the proportions can make the height.
Let's just say 20 pixels for now.
And you can see even though the height is 20 pixels they're not proportionally to scale.
So what I like to do is match the height first and then do some visual balance so we probably want to
be somewhat smaller here.
And if I was to focus more closely on matching the icons I'd probably have a timer with a thinner weight
on it.
But this is good enough I think and do something like this.
And we can change this field to this red color here and now let's zoom out.
So the comment over here the heart here and the time are over here.
I'm just going to add a little bit of text to clicking the Tiki and I'll just call this five hour
and one of seven.
So I'm just going to make sure that these are about four pixels away from the icon.
And I just like to nudge with my arrow keys once I hold down option I can kind of see what spacing looks
like.
And now all align this to the center and group these as one object so that I can align and distribute
them evenly.
OK.
Now that we have this set up you can move this down to be a little bit more balanced.
We have some nice icons here from Icons 8 from Adobe Illustrator and ones that we've created.
Last thing to do here is delete this pian Geographic.
And we should be all set.