Let's talk in more detail about color and to start off with this video I want to show you something
really cool.
Now over the course of these videos we've been using the same color red here throughout a lot of our
art boards.
So what happens when the primary colors need to change mid design.
Well we can click on this icon here because we know that we use the same red as we've used across the
rest of this project.
And it's as easy as clicking this edit button right here.
We can choose to select every object in this file that has the same feel.
So now all of this is selected and I can choose to change this field to blue and automatically our entire
project now has this blue style guide incorporated.
So that's one really quick way to test out new colors and new styles across many our boards in your
project.
Was going to click this go back to select all with the same fill and I'll choose to change this back
to read here.
And you can really change it to any color that you want.
So that's just one powerful way of using some of these filters to select things.
It's the same thing with stroke or different shadow effects if you want to change the shadow effects
across the project.
That all works the same way.
And now with this background color here that we created for the splash screen that's this rectangle
right here we can see that we already added a color feel over top of an image file but we can add multiple
color fills so I can click on the plus icon click on this little color thumbnail and we have a number
of options to add more color to the design so I'm going to click on radial here and we can see that
we have a nice radial image with some anchor handles here to control the width of this radial and also
the height.
Here are the size and we can change the opacity here.
I'm going to change this to 30 percent.
Let's try 60 percent here just to make it a little bit brighter.
And again if I click in here I can decide where the Beginning and End Point is of this.
So maybe if I want to start inside this hand here and then I can have the endpoint something like this
and the width I want it to be a little bit wider.
And you can really just play around with this and you can have a combination of different effects here.
Now inside of the color panel itself if we click on this fill for example we have a number of ways we
can control the color.
We have the color controls down here and the saturation controls in here.
We also have the hex value.
So if you have any other colors that you want to copy from any other program like Adobe Illustrator
or anywhere else you can paste them as a hex value or if there are G-B you can paste those in here.
You also have CSSA values so if you have CSSA properties do you want to copy and paste in here to copy
those colors.
You can do that.
And then the HSP values.
So there are a number of ways that you can add copy and paste colors or paste them outside of here into
other projects.
Another way we can use colors.
Let's go into this recipe details frame here.
And let's look at just this prime rib roast title here.
So I'm just going to zoom in and let's say we spend a little bit trying to find a good color for these
headers.
I'm going to start out with this blue color here and that looks decent but it's not dark enough for
me so I'm just going to pull this down just a little bit and we can see that looks like a really good
color and contrast with this red and we have the hex value here so we could copy this hex value and
we can paste this anywhere else we want to copy that same color.
So I can click inside of here and just do a quick command B and enter and we can paste it that way.
But we know that we're going to reuse this throughout our project quite a bit.
So if I want I can scroll down here and you can see that I have a few color choices.
This is the document colors.
So these are all the colors that have been used in the document and I can just click here to copy that
same color.
Or I can choose personal colors.
These are in my personal collection.
Every time I open figment this is going to be the same palette of colors.
And then I have a chef team colors.
Now you remember in a previous video we created a new team for this recipe's app.
So by doing that we can save this color inside of the color palette anywhere that we want.
I'm going to save this inside of my personal colors as well because I really like this color.
So now.
Because it's in my personal colors I can create a new file here.
This file is completely separate from the other file we were working on.
And if I just draw a rectangle for demo purposes I can click on fill go into my personal colors and
I still have that same color that I can reuse throughout multiple files.
Now you may also notice that we have an opacity control here and when we dial this left and right we
can see that that changes here.
So you have quick access to change the opacity here or down here.
So I someone to leave this at the dark blue.
And one final way to grab and reuse color is if we have a color inside of an image for example that
we want to reuse we can't just double click in here and find out what the field color is for an image
but let's say there's some green inside of here that we want to reuse inside of our project.
Well we can click on any piece of text and I can hold down control C and get this little eyedropper
and it'll show you the hex value here on the top right as you're moving along your mouse to the different
colors.
Or if you click on this color thumbnail you can see that same control here this eyedropper control.
So I'm going to click on this eyedropper tool and I'm going to choose to select a color somewhere around
this area here.
And so very quickly you can grab a color like that and you can save that in your palette for later if
you want to use it.
I actually really like this blue color so I'm going to click back in this color palette and you can
see when I clicked on.
I'm actually using the eyedropper tool still but it gives me the same hex value.
So those are a few ways you can use the color panel inside of your file or inside of your stroke.