In this video we're going to start designing a recipe completed screen.
And by doing this we're going to illustrate some of the style effects that we can create on a pop up
overlay.
Before we go through how to add styles I want to go over here to the recipe details screen and I want
to copy some of these things over to recipe details complete so I could just hover over these elements
and copy and paste onto this our board or I can click on this art board itself and if I go to export
here I can click on this export and I'll just export this at to X and we can see a preview here of what
it's going to look like.
And let's go ahead and export this as a PMG and you can export this anywhere that you want.
I'm going to export this on my desktop and I want to bring it back into the projects so I can click
on the shape's tools click on place image and if I jump into my desktop you can see the recipe details
here.
I'll just click Open and now I'll place this right inside of here and we can scale it however we like.
And here this doesn't look exactly how we want it to.
And remember if we click on this image thumbnail we can use this crop feature and just pull this down
so we see the top of it and all this is is an image hit return here and now it's click inside of your
image to nudge this over to make sure that we have the layering correct.
And now we copied this image inside of here.
And the reason why we did this is we want to create an overlay effect for a pop up menu.
Now to create the overlay color we could click inside of here and add a feel that's a black solid feel
for example and we can do that and turn the opacity down to 40 percent to show that it's overlaid.
But if we do that we can add some effects to just this feel here.
So instead of doing that and going to click on this row and subtract and now all create a rectangle
and drag this over here and I want to create that same black feel with just subtle opacity here and
then one nice thing that I can do here is I can use this effects tool and instead of a draw shadow I
actually want a background color.
So I want the background of anything behind here to be blurred out.
And then I can change this to 20 pixels here to help it become a really blurry.
And now I can change the opacity here let's try 20 percent.
Or 30 percent and we can play with that as much as we want.
In fact I may choose to have this white here.
So now we have a blurred white background and if we drag this rectangle here you can see what it's doing
it's blurring everything behind this rectangle shape.
And I think that's looking really good.
And now we want a pop up window telling us that our recipe is completed.
So we can create another rectangle here.
And I'm just going to make it maybe 240 by 300 right now
and we'll bring this down to the center.
And this may be resized as the content fits in.
And we're going to add new content in a future video.
So now I'll just change this color white I will add a five pixel radius to all the corners.
When I started to look good but we can see that there's very little or no contrast around the edges
here.
So one of the first things we want to do here is just add a subtle stroke
and then we want to jump into our effects once again and this time we just want to add a subtle drop
shadow and for pixel's looks good for pixel Blar it's down for pixels and 25 percent looks decent.
Now we may want to add another châteaux down below.
That's a lot more blurry making this feel like it's popping out of the page quite a bit more.
So if we want to do that we can add a nother drop shadow inside of here.
We can have this be 20 pixel Blar and we can see that that's really pop in that off the page and that's
starting to look really good I'm just going to decrease the opacity here.
And so this is starting to look really good.
But another thing we can do to really help pronounce this pop up is draw a rectangle here to use as
a shadow.
And we'll just make this a little bit smaller than the rectangle here.
And I'm just going to bring this down a few layers.
There we go.
And this rectangle can actually serve as a shadow.
And to do that we can change this color to black.
And now if we jump into and we can change the radius which changes to 30 pixels here.
And now if we go into effects instead of a background blur or a drop shadow or inner shadow that's to
a layer Buhler.
So it's only blurring this actual layer.
And here we want this blur to be 30 pixels Let's start out 30 unless tried maybe 50 pixels here.
So that's looking really good.
And then the actual opacity of this fill let's change this to 15 percent.
And you can hardly see that I'm going to try 30 percent.
Sometimes it's just trying a few numbers to see what works.
So that's starting to look decent here and we can just fiddle around with the sizes.
And what exactly we like.
And I'm going to change this to multiply.
And let's just tweak this little bit more to see what we like.
So we like that should be good.
So we have a nice completed screen here we have some dropshot effects some layer blur effects and some
background blur effects here.
And you can really play with a combination of these effects to get some really nice designs.