In chapter 4 we went over working with content.
And that was working with framed shapes icons and a number of the different tools to apply those to
our design.
So now that we have some well-rounded knowledge on how the tools work there are still some screens left
to be designed here and to apply the knowledge we gained in the previous chapters into completing our
design.
So if you want you can go through these videos with me in completing these designs or you can open up
this chef recipe drawing Panjwaii located in your assets folder and design each one of these screens
based off of the sketches that you see here.
Either way is fine with me.
But if you want to follow along I'm just going to get started with this first video creating a slide
out menu here in the menus frame.
So the first thing I want to do inside of here is create a rectangle using the Arkie for a shortcut
and just create this at 320 pixels and I'm going to use the same red color that we've been using in
previous videos and now that we have this component set up I can go into the components panel here and
drag and drop this button menu somewhere here and I can even line up with this one holding down shift
and selecting.
I can align this to the top and then make sure that this has 20 pixels here against the edge of this
rectangle that will match the same 20 pixels here.
Now very quickly I'm going to add some text so I'll just use the keyboard command and I'm just gonna
start typing these in going to send this to left justify.
OK so we have our four menu items.
I'm going to quickly style this with white text and under the advanced menu I want to transform my text
to uppercase and I want the paragraph height to be 30 pixels here and this text can actually be let's
try 20 pixels right here.
So that's looking pretty decent maybe I'll have a medium.
And now all a lot of this with the edge and hold down shift and the right arrow two times or three times.
So we have our menu here.
And I also want to hit the key for a line and I'll just draw a line that's 30 pixels here and I'll make
this stroke white.
And this can probably be a 5 pixel stroke with the edges rounded.
So I'm going to cap this with a round cap and we can see here we are in popular recipes.
Now we want to hold down option and copy this text down here and just going to add some more text for
the user log in Harry Truman.
And if I tap the key for elipse
created 46 pixel circle she's going to dial that in here because I couldn't get it correct the first
time.
And now that I have this circle selected I'm going to go and fill this with an image.
It's going to ask me to choose the image and I'm going to go into my assets folder here and we can see
this avatar dot and g going to just go ahead and open this up here.
And we have Harry Truman profile image here.
So you can see very quickly we have our menu all designed and set up and in the next video we're going
to finish our pop up screen for the completed recipe.