In this video we're going to complete our on screen overlay screen.
This is the screen that tells them you did it let your friends know about it or leave a review.
So this screen will pop up as soon as they click on this last step here finalizing their preparation.
And that's what we have here.
So in a previous video under the stiles video we already learned how to overlay some of these layers
here so we have a rectangle with a nice background blur.
We have this.
This is just an image of this art board here.
So we exported the image out.
We imported it back into here and now we have these one two three four layers.
So it's an image this blurred rectangle and then we have this pop up overlaid rectangle with some drop
shadows and we have this component that we created in an earlier video too.
So let's complete the rest of this year.
First off we need to add some text and the cool thing about previous our boards and some designs is
I can hold down option and just copy some of these things if I know it's going to be similar to the
same style so I can just type here.
You'd get it.
And right here I'll just use the same text.
Let your friends know about it.
And here it's a little bit wider than I'd like so I can just change that here and holding down shift
I can touch this 10 pixels shift command left arrow left arrow.
I can resize this to be 10 pixels.
So now we have four icons of the Google Plus icon Twitter Facebook Instagram icon and if you want you
can use any icons that you find online for Google Plus Twitter Facebook and Instagram or if you go into
your assets folder.
We have four SVGA icons already for Google Instagram Twitter and Facebook.
So if you want to just use these Lets just hold down shift to select all of these and I'm just going
to drag these in here and we can see that they are all inserted now.
I want to lock the proportions and let's just make the height of each one of these 20 pixels right now
and I can already see that's a little bit big.
So I'm going to change this to 12 pixels and that looks a little bit better.
Now I can align these.
And the first thing I want to do with these icons here is wrap them in their own little circle.
So tapping the Oakey and creating a
20 pixel by pixel circle
I can make the circle red.
And now we'll go in here
and we'll create all of these to be white will center these and bring them over here.
And if I zoom in here I can kind of see what's going on with this Google Plus is a little bit large.
So I'm going to scale this down a little bit.
The width will probably make 16 pixels
and we can play around with this a little bit later on too if they're too unbalanced.
So we'll start right here.
And the last thing here the Facebook icon we want to change this a little bit because we only want this
if we don't want this bounding box so we can double click inside of here a few times and let's look
at our layers panel you can see that this is groups there's an F and on there is a rounded rectangle.
So I'm just going to delete this a rounded rectangle here and now we only have this F so now I can bring
this F over here and resize this and also look a little bit messy right now if we want to we can hide
some of these other ones here as we look at this.
F that's a lot better.
And now that we have all of these selected I'm just going to clean up these layers because it shows
them all grouped.
So let's just look all of these groups holding down shift and I'm going to select shift command G.
And now one more time shift Comanche and I'll just name this social Twitter social Instagram
social Google Plus
social Facebook.
And now I can select a circle and these other social icons you see sometimes and actually didn't put
this in the same frame as the circle.
Sometimes it's a little bit weird like that.
So we want to drag this back down where the circle is.
I'm going to hold out command and select this circle as well and we'll just group everything by creating
a component.
And we're to call this the social component.
Now again we're going to hold down option and copy this and then all right click and move this to the
components page.
And now we have this child component.
This is where we want to start off with the Google Plus icon that will hold down option three more times
and copy this.
And this one we want to be Facebook here we want it to be Instagram.
And here we have this b Twitter.
So we've done a good job already.
But you can still see this is quite large compared to the circle.
So let's right click on one of these and we'll go to the master component and just jumping inside of
here.
I'm going to hide each one and just go ahead and resize some of these things using this scale tool might
help something like that I think will look good.
Let's center that in the our board is Google Plus.
Bring that down a little bit more.
Instagram skill add a little something like this and same thing with Twitter
center that we can jump back into our pages or page one and see how that all looks.
And one thing I forgot to do I'm going to jump back into components is unhide the rest of these.
Jump back in here.
And that looks far more balanced.
Now the last thing I want to do is add some text here to leave a review
and now we want to center all of these things on the watch when I click to drag a drag handle to select
everything I'm actually dragging these things behind.
So this is where the lock layers will come in really handy these two layers right here.
I want to lock now I can click and drag to select everything here except for these circles.
Hold down shift and just click to de-select those.
And now I can align horizontal centers here and I'll align everything here to the frame and also the
center of the frame right here.
Now I can start to align some of these items so I could just choose to add 10 pixels between each of
these icons.
But then right next to each other.
Hold down shift and the right arrow key.
But this next to G shift right arrow key.
All right.
So now let's center this with the overlay and let's put a nice 20 pixels in between there and zero pixels
in between here
and one to three That's 20 pixels.
I'm going hold down shift and one more I'm going to have that 30 pixels here and then down here I'm
going to add 30 pixels here.
And 10 pixels right here.
And when you're asking someone to leave a review here you want this all to be unfilled.
So because this is a component I can choose this first store to hide this field layer.
We're going to also hide this star.
Same thing here same thing here
and now it's blank and ready for them to leave a review.
Last thing I want to do is resize this.
So I want this to also have 30 pixels between the bottom of this pop up window.
And the bottom of these stars so we can see is 26 pixels right here.
So I guess I can just hold down command to resize and set of move and I'll tap this down or one two
three four and we have a nice 30 pixels here and 30 pixels here.
I'll move the shadow to be centered again.
And now I can select everything here.
Hit Comanche to group it and just make sure that this is centered with the frame that it's inside.
The last thing I want to do is add an x ray here so I'll just quickly draw one.
We'll have this two pixels here have this rounded.
And now I'll select this line click command see Command V and quickly rotate.
And for some reason when you rotate it's rotating on this left axis which is a little bit weird but
I can just nudge this using the arrow keys to make it straight.
I just noticed that when I was working with lions they behave a little bit unpredictably but now that
I have this I can click on this union selection and now I have one nice fill all scroll out and I want
to rotate this to 45 degrees and that I can go into object and flatten this selection and change this
to be a nice even size will do 10 pixel by pixel and we'll just make this we hold down shift and nudge
this left once and right once it will just sit 10 pixels away from the edge there.
So now we have a nice pop up menu says you did it.
They can leave a review let their friends know or tap this X and jump back into the recipe.
Now I'm going to hit 0 to zoom out 100 percent see how that looks and it looks really good to me.
But sometimes you have some artifacts there's this edge right here that looks like this.
The edge of this isn't hitting the top even though it is.
So sometimes if you get that it doesn't hurt to grab this shape inside of here and just move it up past
the box just to make sure that you have everything filled inside up here.
So this is how you illustrate an overlay here.
You have to duplicate the image and then place some objects above this.