Now that we have the overlay designed and designed the comments section inside of the recipe details
screen here so you can feel free to design this on your own and match this with what I am doing.
And if you want to do that just pause this video and crank away at the design and then you can resume
this video and see how it closely matches with what I'm talking about here.
But if you want to follow along feel free to do so as well.
So let's scroll down here we're going to jump into the recipe details frame right here.
We can scroll down here and we want to comment section so I know that I can copy something like this.
I'm going to just copy this down.
I'm going to name this comments.
And we know we don't want this same component here.
So I don't want to ruin this component I can right click and detach.
Instance.
So now this is no longer a component.
It's not related to this master component.
And I can hold down shift command G and I can delete this vector image and place in a comment image
so if I go into my components panel here you can see that I've already created some icons here is a
component so I can click and drag this into my art board here and now go back into layers.
I only want this comment I Konst I'm going to hide these two.
And I have that comment.
And you can do this a number of ways but I'm just going to delete this icon here.
I'm going to use this child component and bring this inside of here and you can see that I want this
to match the same exact design as in this art board to the left of it here.
But the color needs to change so there's sometimes there are exceptions to your design.
Just for one time instances and that's where child components really come in handy with overrides.
So I can double click on this layer here and I can create this to be white.
And if you see when I double click inside of here there's this override symbol that's telling me I'm
overwriting the feel and I can always reset that to the master component if I want or just change this
and override it.
Just this one time.
So now I'm going to bring that inside of my circle and I can create this as its own component or a master
component as well and reuse through out other areas if I'd like.
So now I'm going to hit the keyboard shortcut and just a 46 by 46 pixel Avatar.
And here I'm going to hit the T key and just add some text real quick so I'm going to add Tom Kline.
He's a user of our app
and I'm going to make this 13 pixels here and just regular and if I want to match this color of this
font I can do it a few ways but I'm just going to quickly use this eyedropper tool and select something
here.
And you can see that I got barely off where I wanted to select.
So there we go.
And I can see this prime rib roast was amazing.
And it is all caps because under my advanced menu I have that transform control on what I'm going to
toggle this off and maybe I want to have this italics as well.
And the date that he commented was 7 dot 0 1 dot 2017 and I'm going to have this medium just like that.
Now I can quickly set some sizes here just to align this with the base of this.
And one two three four five just nudge this around to your liking.
And this is 26 pixels one two three four five six.
We have that 20 pixels now 10 pixels 10 pixels.
So that's looking pretty good.
And now I can click on the circle I'm going to fill this with an image and I can click on choose image
and I have a few other avatar images.
I'm going to click on Avatar to.
And this is starting to look really good so maybe I'll just say this is a component itself.
So I'm going to click Create component and now this is a master component.
And if I click inside of here I can use this component frame to resize around and you can see that it's
doing some weird stuff.
So I'm going to hit Monsey.
I'm going to set some constraints in this component just real quick so I know that this is always going
to be constrained to the left and the top this is also in fact all of these are going to be constrained
to the left top and then this one here I can constrain this to the left and right.
So it grows as I grow this frame here.
So I'm going to hit the edge of this at 20 and you can see this is now behaving the way I want it.
And now I can hold down option on this component create a child component here and I can override the
text here.
Name this Sally Parker when you see what it did here I had the text aligned at the center so I can go
to the master component here and say I want this to align to the left actually.
And that changes automatically
and now I notice that this text here is running into this text.
So I probably want to add more spacing here so I can hold down shift and maybe I'll do something like
that.
I'm going to fix my spelling here and I'm going to just type in a comment for Charlie Parker.
OK.
So this one's a little bit lengthier but we can see that everything adjusted the right way and it looks
really good.
And lastly we can do a feel override as well so I can click on this image and choose a new image.
I'm going to choose Avatar 3 under our assets folder and go ahead and change that.
And even though this is a master component if I ever want to change this text here it should be rubato
medium black.
Anything else I can change that very easily.
In fact a good example of this if I move this down is I know that I want a five star rating system inside
of here.
And we know we already have that inside of our components so I'm going to click under components here
go to my five star system and I can drag this inside of this component actually.
So now that's dragged inside of there.
I'm going to move the rest of these guys down holding down shift and you can see how everything is just
moving in place and to bring that to the top here.
And I want this to be a little bit smaller actually.
And I can do a scale override on this component as well so if I I'd use the scale tool here down at
the bottom I can hold down shift to constrain my sizes and I want it to be maybe 10 pixels tall something
like that a little bit smaller.
And now I'll just adjust the rest of these to be 10 pixels or five.
One two three four five five pixels from the stars and I'm going to move this up here to just almost
hit this.
And very quickly you have your comments in here.
Now the last piece I'm going to create is a little type your comment here widget down here so I'm going
to hit R for rectangle.
Draw a rectangle here that is 40 to 45 pixels here.
And remember we already created a user persona for this design and that was Harry Truman.
So I can click this avatar here and hold down option.
I'm just going to copy this down here and reuse this.
And here maybe I want the avatar to be 32 pixels.
Going to line this to the left it at 20 pixels here.
And add some text here type your comments here.
Now I can reuse the same icon that we used previously.
I'm going to go into my layers panel and hide the rest of these.
So that's looking good and I'll sit that 20 pixels from the right here.
The last thing I want to do is create a White feel and instead of a stroke if we add a stroke here you
see that you have strokes round the edges.
I don't want that.
So I can show you how to add just a top and bottom strokes here if we go under effects and drop shadow
we can actually add a 1 pixel drop shadow that has a zero pixel blur.
And that shows up is a stroke or a line.
I'm going to make that 10 pixel opacity.
So it's pretty light and I can just create a new one here and I'll do the same thing except negative
one 10 percent opacity zero pixel blur and you can see we have a top and bottom line here.
Now I'm going to select all of this create a new component and when I do that I'm just going to make
sure that everything's pinned to the top left how it should be here.
This should be pinned to the center and well to the wall to the left here and also to the center down
here.
And this could be pinned to the right center.
And now I'll just stretch this something like this and change the opacity to 20 percent.
And the last thing you want to do is resize our frame so we're in a click on the frame here.
Come down here and just resize this.
I'm going to hold down command to zoom in.
And now if I hold down option I can see that this is 36 pixels from the base of this.
So again one two three four five six holding down command and the arrow keys.
And then if I hold down Shift one to three that will move at ten pixels three times.
So you have a nice snug component in our frame also we can try resizing as we see that everything looks
really good.
And I'm going to pin this to the left and right.
So now let me resize it.
It kind of breaks down here.
Looking really good.
Same thing with these components just really quickly top left.
These are all top left left right.
So this is looking good.
I can resize this now.
It's looking really decent.
And then these guys we want just to be centered top center.
There we go.
We can move these around.
We're just playing with some spacing now just to get things looking good.
I haven't had an exact spacing convention in here mainly because I just wanted to use this time to teach
you the actual tools and later going to go in and fix a lot of the spacing.
While we're inside here we have some alignment issues for some of these things.
I'm just going to select all of them and align horizontal centers and our design is starting to look
really clean here.
We did change the text here to blue and we didn't change those here.
So again option command see then we can select these layers an option command V and paste those layers
in.
It's going to clean up some things make this all caps here and this is looking really really good.