Our design is looking really good and it's almost ready to prototype.
But we're missing a few designs that I think are key to prototyping this correctly and that is when
we click on appetizers entrees or desserts we want to see how that toggle looks between this.
So to do this we're going to create some more frames here and I'm just going to move these over here
to the right to make some room.
And now I can hold down option and I'll copy this two times.
I'm going to rename this frame here it's named home but I'm just going to name this whole entrées.
I'll name this one home.
Appetisers.
And this one home desserts sort of show you how these toggles work.
Let's just go in here.
I'm going to zoom into all three of these and I'll show you how you can change each of these.
So here we have the entrees all correct.
This is the appetizer screen.
So to change the state here I'm actually going to hold down command.
And if you hold down command it will drill inside of a group.
Right now I'm just selecting a group.
But if you want to select elements inside of the group without double clicking them multiple times just
hold down command.
I can click on entrées and with some quick shortcuts option commands see to copy the style Option Command
V to paste the style and then I'm going to select dessert.
Do the same thing Option Command see Option Command B and paste this.
I'm just going to move this line now over here and stretch this out a bit.
Holding down option to lock my left and right symmetry here.
So now we show appetisers the same thing with the zurr.
I'm just going to change this here so it's the same process command see Option Command B option command
see Option Command V and then I'll move this line over here to dessert.
And just nudge this.
And now we have entrees appetizers desserts inside of our assets folder I have some text that we can
copy here for the appetizers and for the desserts.
So we have their recipe breadsticks text file for the appetizers and the recipe shortcake text file
for the dessert so we can quickly just select this command see to copy and we'll click in here a few
times and come in vi and we'll just call this breadsticks
and now with home desserts we're going to use this strawberry shortcake command C Manby and I'll just
name this here.
So now we have Prime Rib breadsticks strawberry shortcake.
Now I want to change the rating of these bread sticks here.
I'm actually going to give this four stars.
So that's looking good.
And if I want to give this four stars as well I'm just going to delete that and to make life simpler
I'm just going to come and see.
Click on this frame and command the
and I notice here that this isn't centered so we can quickly use the center icon and center our star
ratings and I'm going to hold down shift to select all of these I'm just going to nudge this down a
little bit so it's a little bit further away from this image.
Now for the images all we have to do is click inside of here quick choose image we have our assets folder
here or look for some breadsticks here.
And then the rest of the appetizer images we have to click on this x to get out of there and click on
this group double click a few times until we see this image thumbnail and we'll choose a new appetizer
or these caprice.
It's like mozzarella cheese with some tomatoes.
And the last appetizer here is going to be
hot wings.
Love the hot wings.
So we have that set up and do the same thing over here.
We know we want a strawberry shortcake.
Let's go into our desserts dessert right here strawberry shortcake.
And to the left
we can add
this chocolate cake and feel free to google your own images and place whatever you want in here.
I'm just showing you the workflow for creating and duplicating some of these designs.
The last time I'm going to have is dessert ice cream cobbler.
OK so we have home on trees.
Home appetizers and home desserts.
We zoom out here.
We can see we have a nice complete design here and we're ready to finally wrap things up on the design.