Now that we've designed all of the elements inside of each one of these frames I want to challenge you
to give this design your own personality.
You can use your own colors your own fonts and try playing around with the icons the sizes and everything
else to make this app really your own.
I'll also add some time on this design just adding a few minor elements here to really give it a nice
polish by using the skills that you learned in the previous video.
You should be well-rounded and be able to adjust a lot of these designs here adjust the text and anything
else that you would like.
One thing that I was interested in doing here is I was designing this is giving some of the shapes like
this a little bit more organic feel so I could double click into this for example and I can just tweak
this circle just a little bit to make it look kind of like a a catch up blob.
So we can do something like that just to give it a little bit more personality.
And so try things like that and try different fonts.
So for example I like the font Fat Frank so I can click on some of these text elements here and go into
the text just type in Fat Frank and everything changes here.
Looks like I have some extra text inside of here so I'm just going to delete that and move this back.
And so already there some added personality here and I can Option Command see to copy this style and
even paste it crossed other elements here.
So play with the corner radiuses here.
Play with the sizes and when you're done with the design Feel free to add me as a collaborator.
You can use the email kilobit brain spin dot com to share your designs with me and I'm happy to comment
and give you advice along the way with your design.
Also if you want to share any parts of your design whether it's on Twitter or Facebook Instagram just
use the hash tag Ficke my recipe and I'll be watching out for that hash tag and I can give you some
comments and feedback there.
OK so I've added some finishing touches here and I can walk you through what I've done.
I went and tweets the font here this was a handwritten font using the pencil tool so I just tweaked
the sizes to keep it more consistent.
And then I used the Fat Frank font here for some of the hetter texture the menu text.
I use that across the project here and I changed my paragraph text to be burial which is a font that
I really like.
And so it just gives it just a little bit more personality here.
It just looks a little bit more fun and we can come down here.
I play it a little bit with the line heights and I also made these circles just a little bit more organic
here and same thing here.
So it looks like just like a drop of catch up or something.
And lastly under the comments window I just created a light gray rectangle here to kind of divide the
comments section from the rest of this.
And I actually forgot the style of this fund here so I'm just going to copy and paste this here.
So now we have all of our art boards all designed and lined up here and we are ready to begin prototyping.