In the last video we created a brand new project and a new file the chef underscore recipe underscore
app.
But what if you've started your project already inside of a program like sketch or what if you want
to start with a template and build your designs out from there.
He does really good with importing sketch files and maintains the quality in the layering scheme that
you would expect to give you an example of this.
I'm going to go into our exercise files under the assets folder and you can see we have a recipe app
template sketch file here that we can import.
Now you can drag and drop in a sketch file directly into this project or you can browse the way that
I did and click open.
And while this is loading this happens to be a template that I found on a Web site called Sketch app
sources now Sketchup sources have tons of templates whether it's the IRS template guidelines material
design you can see some Tesla dashboards here so feel free to go onto this Web site and browse these
thousands of templates and if there's something that you like with a certain flavor that matches where
you'd like to start you can click download resource here and then import it later here into Sigma.
Now this is important.
We'll click dumb.
And now you can see this template here.
And if we double click inside of here we can see how this looks.
Now one of the first things that we can see is we may not have the fonts that were used in this template
so you can go online and find these or use type kits to find certain fonts and load them before you
get started with your design.
Or you can just dismiss this and update your fonts later.
We can see that this sketch template had two pages if we click on here we can see a symbol's page and
then a page one.
So this is where they retained all of their symbols inside sketch and these symbols are converted into
Master components which is really great to go back to PAGE ONE here and we can see these different frames
and we see that the background is gray.
So we have a hard time distinguishing the boundaries between some of these frames.
So all we have to do is go to this background area and change this to be like gray and we can kind of
see the contrast there between the frames and the background here.
And another thing that you notice is although it retains a lot of the layering schemes and some of this
font here there are times where some layers may not import correctly.
So if we go to this log in and sign up for example there are some missing text here between the log
in and sign up by him and things like that.
So it may be worth your while to open up the sketch program and find the few layers that may be missing
and add those in manually.
But you can see how much time this will save you getting started with Fig.
If you're starting with a sketch file.