In a previous video we set up a team and that's this chef team and this is where we set up a project
here for our chef recipe app.
If you skipped this video you can click here to set up a new team and name this team whatever you want.
I'm going to hit cancel here because I already have one created.
But if you haven't go ahead and create this team and once you do you'll get this little view here for
your team and you can see inside of this chef's team.
I have a one project here but I don't have any team members working with me to really harness the power
of Sigma.
I want to invite a new team member here so I'm going to click on this in a team member and I'm just
going to type in somebody's email
you can type in multiple people's email and this text field and then you can choose what access they
have to the projects inside of this team.
So whether they're an admin of the team or they can edit any projects within this team or only view.
So here I'm going to give them admin access and I'll just click and buy here their name and their avatar
is going to be grayed out until they accept my invite.
And once they do they'll see the same team here when they log in to Sigma they'll see all the projects
that you're seeing and they can click at any time and edit regardless of if someone already has this
project open.
If you have any questions or would like help throughout this course feel free to add me as a team member
inside of your project as well.
You can add me at Caleb ADD brain spin dot com.
And once I accept your invite you will be able to use the comment feature to ask me specific questions
and I can jump in and help you resolve them.
After she has accepted the invite you can see the name and Avatar here.
So now if I click on my chef recipe project here we can see that we have these two files here.
And we've invited one member to our team and now we can see Marleen is in this file here.
So if I want to collaborate with here I can double click and you'll see her mouse here and her avatar
here saying that she's actually interacting with the design.
So now we're going to ask her to drag this home our board around.
And you can see her dragging that live.
And if you want to follow her mouse while she's doing that just click on her avatar here and it'll follow
her as she interacts with things.
So maybe drag that back up to the top here.
And you get a nice view here of what she's doing and this is really helpful if your background has a
100 art boards and you're not sure where she's interacting with a certain are bored.
Just click on this name here and it'll zoom the canvas right in to where she's working.
So now I've asked Marleen to add some text into the sign in and sign up button so she's going to go
ahead and do that now.
And while she's filling in that content I can style this for her so let me zoom in here and I can see
that she already typed this sign in button so I can go in here and change this to be white.
Change the font size to be 16.
And if I want to start out with the size I can hold down Option Command C to copy the style Option Command
V to paste it over here and then I just want to change this color.
So I'm going to change this to the same orange right here and get started here.
So you can see how easy and how close I can be designing with her as she is creating content and I'm
stylize ing it.
And then I can go and hold down option and bring this text over here or sign in and here for sign
and this is also very helpful if you're on an online screen sharing session with a client or with a
collaborator to have them open up the enigma as you are and you guys both designing together as you're
discussing your project is very powerful and very helpful.