Inside the assets folder under exercise files you'll find this design templates text file.
Now this text file just has a link to these four resources here.
You find design templates and these templates come in very handy.
For example if you're designing for iOS 11 you can go to developer Apple dot com and they have design
resources in this link here for scatch for Adobe XTi for other design files.
And remember if it is a sketch file you can import that directly into Sigma and start from there.
Alternatively if you're designing for Android you can get the material design template here and material
Dyo.
And these two links below are community resources for sketch files and for Sigma files.
So take a minute to visit these links and familiarize yourself with a few templates because it could
really help save some time.
For example if you download the iOS 11 design template from developer to Apple dot com you get this
folder and not only does it give you the sketch files here the production templates but it also gives
you the fonts used inside of this template so you don't find missing fonts once you load this up into
a figure so you can click inside here you can see that we have all of the San Francisco pro font packages
that come with the iPhone design.
Then we have production templates here that are for app icons or for navigation Flo's and the last folder
here we have UI elements designs and guidelines.
And you can hit the spacebar on a Mac and kind of see a preview of the elements that you're going to
get once you import this template into figure.
I would highly encourage you to save these links in your bookmarks folder because as you're continuing
to design these are going to come in very handy.