Finally we are ready to prototype our design now prototyping is really easy and you can find the prototyping
tab here next to the Design tab.
And once you click on this prototyping tab then you get this circle here to the right of every object
that you select that you can click and drag to link your boards up.
So if we're starting off with the splash screen you want to go from the splash screen to the home entrées
screen here and I'm going to zoom in here so we can see just in a little bit more detail what I'm doing.
And as you can see with these three screens we want to link these up by clicking on appetisers to jump
to this page.
And entrées to jump to this page.
But they're all inside one group.
Well that's OK we could link the group to other art boards but that's not going to work in our case
so we can double click to drill into just this desert text here and we can drag this over to desert's
and we don't need to link up entrées because we're on the entrées page we can link up appetisers and
same thing here on trees goes here.
Desert's goes here and same thing here on trees.
Appetisers So we already have those links up.
Now we can select these menu items and link these up here.
And looks like those are all correct.
And now we're going to run into a bit of a problem here.
We have these hyperlinks here I created this all in one text box and this works OK and most design cases.
But if you want to prototype this you can only prototype this one box.
So it's not going to work for us.
So we can jump back into design here.
And I'm just going to select this text here and do a command X to cut it.
And now we'll just copy these elements down here.
I'll paste this in to the same thing.
Cut down here.
Paste this and cut this last text and paste again.
These have to be individual text boxes just for the sake of prototyping.
So now I want these to be 30 pixels apart.
And that looks good now.
So we can jump back into prototype mode.
And now I can jump into popular recipes is going to be this page here.
And we didn't design a saved recipes shopping list or setting screen.
But if you wanted to design some screens to kind of mock up this interaction you can do that and then
just link to your saved recipes after you design something like that.
So this will work for what we have so far.
And so this menu actually we want this to link back to the popular recipes as well kind of a slide back
and forth type of thing.
Now if the user clicks on this image we want that to link to the recipe details screen and maybe this
title to sort and link this to the recipe details as well.
And then as we're going down this list if the user clicks on this last step checking it off they're
going to get this screen saying you did it share with your friends and they can click on this x here
to jump back.
Or maybe this background image they can click on here and jump back as well.
So I think we have everything linked up and we can test it very quickly just to make sure.
So we have the start screen right here.
We can move it anywhere we want but we're going to leave this at the splash screen here and we'll just
go into present mode and let's see how well we've done.
We have the design chefe screen.
You can click anywhere to jump into our popular recipes.
And let's just see how this menu works here so we can click there or click back that toggle works great.
Or we can click on popular recipes here and we can toggle between appetizers entrees and desserts here.
So that's looking really good.
And I probably should have changed the timing because it doesn't take five hours for strawberry shortcake
but you can change that if you want.
Now we have that all set up and you can see if I click here nothing happens because we don't have a
strawberry shortcake recipe.
We don't have a breadsticks recipe but we do have this prime rib roast so that's going to jump us into
this.
And you see how this is zoomed out to show us the entire board.
Well what we want to do is change this feel area to display it 100 percent always.
So now this behaves a little bit more like what you would see on the iPhone.
Now one thing I've noticed while prototyping and this is why prototyping is so helpful.
I don't have a way to jump back into that home screen so very quickly I can still jump into my prototyping
file and we can see down here we need an x icon.
So we're just going to zoom into these two boards.
I'll go back into design and I already have an X-ray here that I can use.
I'll just hold down option and bring this over here and just lay this in the center somewhere and I'm
going to make the field white and I probably want to make this a little bit bigger.
So 20 pixels by 20 pixels and that's looking good.
I think that'll be a nice X screen.
The last thing I'm going to do is just add a subtle drop shadow here of 50 pixel opacity and zero pixels
vertically.
So we have that nice x.
We can still jump into our prototyping present mode and we can see that we have that X now but if we
go back into our design and go into prototype you now I can choose to have this x come back over to
entrées jump back into my prototyping and now I can toggle back and forth between these.
So again as you prototype you'll see things like this where you may get stuck in the prototyping or
the interaction and you'll have to go back into your design add some buttons and then test again to
make sure that somebody can go through your design.
The last screen we have right here is we can check off this last step and we have this congratulations
you did it screen and we can click X to jump back into our prime rib roast.