As you're designing your app Sometimes it's really helpful to see what these screens are going to look
like directly on your device and to do that has a nice app for Android and for iPhone.
And it's called the Sigma mirror app.
So just look in the Google Play store for Sigma mirror or look in the Apple App Store for fig mimir.
And once you download this app you can sign in using your log in name and password and you'll be presented
with a screen that tells you to click on a frame on your desktop to see what it looks like on your phone.
So here we have the home entrées frame.
And when I click on this you can see that our iPhone updates showing us what this frame looks like directly
on the device.
And one thing that's really nice about this is you can tweak your sizes you can move things around and
these things happen live directly on your device as well.
So sometimes I like to design some icons that are quite large here and you don't know how large they're
going to be in relation to your device.
And so it's nice to look at that and then do a quick resizing here to make the sizes relative to your
screen and make the tap area large enough so that you can't miss it.