Now if you Adamy collaborators using this share icon you can add them to only view or to edit the design
itself.
But all collaborators they have access to this design all have the ability to comment.
So if I click Show comments here you'll be able to interact with multiple collaborators by clicking
on a frame and just typing something like those breadsticks look yummy.
And they have some basic emoticons that you can use and you just hit post and there's my comment if
there's any comments for feedback of somebody giving you feedback on color changes or padding.
If you finished you can click this resolve button here and you can see that they're hidden in the list
of comments.
You can toggle the results comments on and off here.
And if you toggle them back on you can unresolved them if they need further editing.
Also any collaborators that you share with this project any time that you comment anything than I have
right here unable to receive e-mail notifications.
So if I share this with anybody and they comment I'm going to get an e-mail that shows me what they
call him and I can click on the e-mail link and jump right into the frame that they're commenting on.