After you've finished with your design and you're testing out the prototype and everything looks really
good you probably want to export some of these assets for your developers to use.
A good way to do this is to look at each screen.
So we have this screen right here with the chef's icon and then some custom text here.
So I'm going to just group all of this text.
I'm going to name this title chef's recipe and here I'm just going to name this icon chef's hat.
And you just want to make sure that all of your graphics are named correctly the name that you want
the file to export as.
And now if you click on this export button here we can see that there 0 0 0 selected designs.
That's because if we want to use this we want to make these graphics exportable so we can click on this
plus icon here and we can choose to export this as PMG JPAC or SPG.
Now if we choose g we can export this at its exact pixel size.
Or if we want to add a two times or three times you can just keep on hitting this plus icon and it will
create some multiple sizes here.
So we have a 2 x 3 x and if we want text appended to the filename.
That's what this is doing here so it's going to say Icahn's chef's hat at 2 x at 3 x so very quickly.
I'm enabling these two to be exported one time to time three times.
And let's go over here.
The same thing we want to make sure that these are named correctly so we can just name this timer name
this hard.
Just really quickly you probably have different naming conventions.
But just make it really simple for your developers to find what they want and you want to do this throughout
all of the designs here.
But let's just use these three so I can select all three of these and come down here I'm going to hit.
Plus it's exploiting those as one time two times three times right here.
So now I don't have to have anything selected because I've preset those to be exportable.
I can click on this export now and it will tell me there's 15 graphics that are going to be exported.
And you see this is one time two times three times.
And this is giving me an error that the origin is not aligned to pixels but we can quickly click export.
I'm going to just export this to my desktop and I'll create a new folder called assets
and hit save.
And now when I go into my assets folder under my desktop when I created these you can see the names
of these comments at 2 x at 3 x and so very easily I can see what these look like.
So this is three times two times in one time they are different sizes and you can pass these off to
your developer to use while they're developing the front end of this design.
Another thing you can do to export assets for your developers is just share this fig file with them
and they don't have to know how to design.
They just have to know how to grab these elements and even Mark some of these elements themselves as
exportable.
So for example if we click on this home on trace here and we go to the code section your developer can
still click on these icons they can name them whatever they want here and they can choose to export
these however they want to export these whatever is going to be the best format for them and they can
export these individually so if they click export button menu for example they can go into the same
folder and click save.
And if we jump back in to here we can see that those are also saved here.
So it's very easy to export these things out.
And in fact once you preset these elements if you ever change them in the future and click to re-export
it'll just overwrite over those existing images and create new fresh versions automatically.