To show you the design panel I have a simple art board here with a few elements on them and this design
panel will change depending on what you have clicked on.
So here we have a basic home screen for our recipe Web site.
And when we don't have anything selected this design panel reflects the canvas or the background that
the frames are sitting on.
So here we can change the color of this background if we want it to be more dark for example or if we
want the background to show in some exports and we can also change the transparency and choose to enable
pixel preview or pixel grid preview right here.
So all of our design properties are around the background here because we don't have anything selected.
So when we select this chef's hat we can see the properties changed to reflect this hat so we can still
move this around and we can move the x and y coordinates here.
And you see the properties panel is changing.
And we can also resize the width and the height and we can lock the proportions.
So if I want to change the height here to be 30 then the width is going to change to reflect that ratio.
You can also quickly change the rotation by 15 degrees.
And also if you hold down command while you're hovering over these anchor points you can rotate them
with your mouse as well.
Now one really nice feature and Figment are the constraints tools with these tools we can constrain
any objects to the left on top of this our border frame or we can pin it to the right or the center.
So we have all of these controls to constrain our objects for responsive design.
For example this one if I choose to scale this I'm going to click on this desktop frame now and I'm
just going to resize this and you can see that both of these items scale here.
Now I'm going to hold down Kamensky and undo that.
We don't want this to scale what we wanted to do is pinned to the top left here.
This one compared to the top left and maybe these guys here can pinned to the top right.
So we have those set up and now and we rescale this.
You can see up the top here that behaves how it's supposed to.
So as you can see there's very nice controls here for constraints.
And then we have a layer section and this is where we can get some overlay settings if we want something
to multiply.
So why it multiplied by anything is that color changes to red you can kind of see how it's transparent.
I'm going to hold out command here and zoom in so you can kind of see what that's doing.
But you can play with some different overlay effects here and get a nice style that you want.
I'm just going to change this back to white and just normal is fine.
So you have some nice opacity effects here you can increase the transparency here or just simply hide
the layer if you want to.
And then you have full control so this is where you'll change the actual color and we saw that as I
was changing this around so you can change this to blue and we can create a feel on top of a feel which
is really great.
So if I click on the plus icon here you can see that I have a linear feel on top of a solid feel so
that gives us this nice white on top of blue and I can change the angle of these pretty quickly.
And just get a nice effect if I want something like that looks good.
And so multiple fill options.
And within this fill color you can fill with the solid color a linear color radial angular diamond or
an actual image.
So if you click on image here that's going to ask you to choose an image and you can find one in your
file and fill that image.
If I ever want to delete a feel I can just click on the file here and just click this subtract button
and then I'll remove that.
And now I'll turn this back to white.
And we have stroke.
And again we can create multiple stroke colors.
I'll just create this as blue and I want this to be on the outside of the icon and you can change the
weight you have some nice dash settings if you want that stroke to be dashed if you want the dashes
to be kept things like that.
Now we also have some effects settings and I'm going to show you if I hold down a command and just scroll
down or zoom out here and you can see this background here.
We actually have two effects here.
So when you click on the plus icon it adds a new effect.
And here I'm going to just delete this one and then you can choose between an inner shadow drop shadow
layer Blar or background blur.
Now this background blur is really nice because you have the ability to turn down the opacity and when
to turn this to 70 here so we can kind of see what's going on in the background.
And you can see this layer is blurred the background and these settings can be changed right here.
So I can decide I want this to be a 30 pixel Blar and you can see it's becoming more blurred.
And then just turn the opacity however you want to see that blur in the background.
Maybe I'll turn this to 90 and same thing with drop shadow.
Just click this icon to see the blur settings and if you want a y coordinate here if you want to draw
the shutter down to pixels that will happen here.
And you can change the opacity here and also some overlay effects for that shadow itself.
So very powerful controls just for basic shapes like these icons or these rectangles.
You can also see this rectangle shape.
I've actually removed the feel.
So if it starts out with the feel you can just click over here and click the subtract icon and I'll
remove that fill.
And now I only have a stroke and with this stroke I've actually created a dashed line here so you can
see that here there's a two pixel dash and a 2 pixel gap.
And if I click away you can kind of see that Dashon gap here.
So with the chef's icon with this rectangle and these icons we get the same kind of design panel here
that's meant for vector shapes but now when I click on this background here and we can see although
this looks like an image it's actually a rectangle with an image feel applied.
So we have this image fill here and then we have a black 20 percent opacity layer feel on top of that.
And then we have a linear feel just for the top.
Just to give a little black transition down so this text is easier to read here.
So this is all one object and it has three different layers and makes it very nice to quickly go in
and change some of these.
So let's say maybe I only want a 5 percent opacity here we can change that very easily.
And if I want to edit this image at all I can click on this little thumbnail and I have some nice exposure
controls if I want to change the exposure some contrast change that here and we can change the temperature
if we want it to be warmer colder.
You can do that very easily and then we have other controls like tint highlights and shadows now one
thing I haven't shown you yet are the alignments and the distribution tools.
So if I click on this like on here and let's just mess this up a little bit just drag these around here
if I want these to be aligned I can hold down shift and just select the multiple items here.
And I have some alignment controls up here to align things to the top line into the bottom.
Now these are the same height so top and bottom are both aligned or aligned center.
And then we also have distribute a horizontal spacing which will make sure that this has the same spacing
between each icon.
So if I want it I can click on these icons just align them to this text here.
And do that to start out with and then hold down shift and select these different objects and will distribute
these evenly will align them evenly.
And now we can move this text to be aligned with this object itself.
So very nice to just have a clean design here.
And now with different text layers you can see we have some of the similar properties like constraints.
We can resize here very easily but now we have a text section and this is where you going to change
your font styles your weights and the sizes.
And if it's multiple lines of text like we see here down below we can change things like the line spacing.
I'm going to change this to 120 percent and you can see how that spacing increases here.
Also the spacing between characters so if you want to increase that by 15 percent we can do that and
maybe I'll just do 5 percent because that was a bit dramatic and also paragraph spacing so if you want
to change this to 20 you can see only the paragraph was spaced.
Now we can align this text to the top of the bounding box the center of the bounding box or the bottom
of the bounding box.
So now if we change this bounding box to be taller we can change where that lives inside of this box.
We also have paragraph indentation and some alignment tools that you find in common text editors.
But there are some hidden effects here as well.
So if we drag this down here and we click on this advanced menu we have things like auto resize the
width and you can see what that did here it made it as wide as the text allows.
I'm going to hit undo and we have some other objects like transform this to all upper case or lower
case or just correct capitalization.
And then we have some underline or strikethrough effects here.
Makes it very handy.
And then we have some more advanced font features like Fraction's all smallcaps superscript or subscript.
And then we can change the way fonts are lined by proportional alignments tabular proportional style
or tapping their old style so a lot of great advanced features for fonts as well as the normal stroke
effects layers and constraints sections that you get with other objects.
Now there's one more section we haven't talked about here and that's the export section and this is
with every object that you select.
You have the ability to export that object.
So we have three icons here and let's say you want to export this out as we develop for the iPhone.
Well we can click on this plus export and we can see that this is going to export as a one time PMG
and we can change this to JPEG or SPG.
But if we only want peahen G We can click plus a few times to even export this out as two times resolution
three times resolution and get multiple file sizes with just one export of this spoon.
Same thing with this fork.
Just click this one to three and you have three different sizes that are going to be exported and this
knife.
One two three.
So with this we can quickly quick preview and see how this is going to look in the preview and then
export this file into any folder that you want.
Now because I set these to be exportable if I ever change them and then export it'll actually export
the changes and I can click on this tool here to export in bulk all of the items I've already set previously
to be exportable.
They'll all be here so I can do a one time export of everything in my project.