The prototype panel is where are you going to go to connect all of your art boards for an interactive
prototype and that lives right next to this design tap here so I'm going to click on this prototype
tab and it's first going to ask what you want the background to be when you're in prototype mode and
to jump into prototype mode you click on this present icon and it opens up a new tab and this tab will
show you what this prototype is going to look like and I can jump into this tab here to link up this
prototype and I can toggle between these two tabs to see my prototype or my design.
So it's very simple to link up a prototype.
We can see if I scroll here to the left a little bit and I click on this log and page here there's a
circle here this new to this bounding box.
And I can click and drag on this circle to present a wire that I can bring to any other art board and
link up.
Now instead of doing that I can also just click on the log in button itself and I'll double click inside
of here and we can see the same circle.
So this log in button I want to go to the home page.
And so just watch how quickly I can link up this prototype here.
Here's the hamburger menu.
I'm going to double click into there and that will open up this page and if I zoom in a little bit I
can quickly link up these menu items so I can double click into exhibitions in advance if I want to
link up the shopping the collections.
And I think we have tickets.
That's plan your visit and one more is the membership.
So become a member.
So now those are all linked up.
And if I double click inside of here we can link all of these back into this menu icon
and now I can choose to have this area go back to this art board here or let me change this and change
it to go back to this art form.
So we should have everything linked up and we can see here there's this little home icon saying this
is where your prototype is going to first land.
So I can click on this and I can bring this in the other place that I want and that's how this prototype
panel does for you as it just enables you to have quick access as to why are these art boards up then
you can click on this play icon which is right here.
It'll tab back over here and then you can interact with a prototype opening the menu item going to exhibitions
go into your collections and just jump through your prototype very easily using the tools in the prototype
panel.