If you're wondering if sigma is right for you it's good to understand what pigment is.
Figma is an online design tool that lets you design prototype and gather feedback all in one place
because your designs are in the cloud
You never have to upload download or worry about versions within Figma
You can create design teams and work together with dozens of people at the same time.
Developers can join and inspect and export or copy code for product development.
Your marketing team can jump in and edit copy and images and you can quickly communicate design ideas
by sharing interactive prototypes with a link.
Figma is an awesome tool for large design teams that want to work closely together without any friction
and is currently the only design tool with this amount of collaborative power.
Think of Google Docs for designers.
If this feels like the right tool for you.
Join me in future videos as I explain these features in more detail.