Now they were signed up for figment we can see the start screen here and this is where we get access
to all of our files.
So we have three sample files that figure has given us and we can always double click into there to
open those files.
But if you want more options with those files you just click on this more menu here and we have other
options like sharing duplicating renaming things like that.
Now we have different ways of browsing our files over here on the left.
We can browse by most recent the drafts or deleted files and we can also create new teams so we can
share files inside of teams for different collaborators.
And this is where you're going to create new teams.
I'll talk more about this in a future video but this is where you're going to be able to find your teams.
Also if you want to change any account settings you can click on this down arrow here and we can change
our account settings and we can also get the desktop app and I'm going to show you how to do that in
a future video as well.
Now if you don't want to start off with the figure file we can actually import files here so we can
import figment sketch files images different things like that if we want to start off with a different
document.
Now over here to the right is the notifications icon and we're not going to see any notifications yet
but as people start to collaborate with you and they start to comment and things like that you're going
to find those notifications here.
Lastly if you have any questions about Sigma there's this help and resources icon here where you can
get access to some video tutorials.
The community forum and things like that.