Let's talk about what you can find inside the Sigma menu bar to the right I have Sigma open in a web
browser and to the left I have the open inside of the fig my desktop app and there are many benefits
to running this inside of the app and that starts with the menu screen and in both of these windows
I'm going to open up a new file.
And if you don't have any existing files you can just click on new file.
It doesn't matter what file you open up I'm just going to show you the menu bar.
So I'm going to click on both of these to open them up.
And first off with the menu bar as you can see we have File Edit View history bookmarks people window
help.
And this is the Chrome browser.
But if I click on Fig MMA now you have things that are associated with the Enigma object vector text.
And these tools come in really handy when you're designing with stigma.
You can find these same menu options inside of the Chrome browser if you click in Chrome click on this
hamburger menu and you have some of these same things.
I'm going to discuss the menu items inside the app but if you are using Chrome or in other web browser
you can follow along in this hamburger menu going from left to right here we have file.
And this is where you can start new projects or files you can close and open tabs and you can also save
your projects as a dot Fig.
Now when you're usually editing projects you don't have to save as you're editing because everything
is a lie.
And on the browser.
But if you want to save an off line instance to store or archive you can click on the Save as fig or
you can export different files in your project here within the Edit menu we have a typical undo redo
cut copy and paste.
And we also have paste in place and then some great tools that we have our pick color.
So if there's already a color that you like inside of your project you can choose this pick color and
click anywhere within this canvas to choose that color and any objects that you have selected will adopt
that color.
You can also set default styles for shapes that you're creating.
So when I click on this rectangle tool and I just draw a rectangle here the default style is this gray
color if I choose to have this black and I have a purple stroke for example and I choose the weight
of the stroke to be 10 pixels.
Now I can click on this object I can go to Edit and set default style.
And now when I click on this rectangle again and draw a new rectangle it's always going to adopt that
same style about I set.
Now there's also copy style and paste style.
So again if I draw these two rectangles here I can set a style here.
Let's change this back to white and instead of changing this one back to White I can click here.
Copy this style and then click onto this object and paste the style here and it will adopt the same
styles that I have set.
You can also choose to select all and that select everything within the canvas which are just these
two objects right now you can select none.
Or if I select this guy and go into edit and select Inv. this will select everything besides what I
already have selected which is this object here.
Now there are also some great selection filters that are very powerful so to illustrate this I'm going
to copy these two objects here and I'm going to hold down option and drag to duplicate these.
And with these two objects I'm going to change the fill.
Let's change it to black again.
And now with these objects if I click one of these and go into edit I can select everything that has
the same style.
So if I click on this it's going to select only these two objects or I can choose to select all just
with the same fill.
And that's also again going to be these two objects.
And so you can see kind of what this is doing.
You can select every element within your project that has the same text and then you can quickly change
that text throughout your project even if it's through 100 art boards or frames.
You can change that text within seconds.
These may sound like very simple options but allows for powerful editing techniques.
And lastly if you want to add any emoji or symbols into your design you can find those here now to show
you things inside of the view menu.
First I have to create a frame and we'll talk more about this later but I just want to create one real
quick to illustrate how the view menu works show pixel grid works if you enable this it will show you
the pixels themselves.
If I zoom in holding down command you can see this little grid showing each individual pixel.
So that comes in handy when you're trying to place your design on pixels.
You can also show layout grids.
So it's enabled right now but we don't have a layout so I'm going to just click plus and you can see
that that shows the grid.
Or you can hide this.
There are other view options like shole mask outlines of your masking some objects together you can
kind of show where those outline are bounding boxes are.
You can show the rollers here height and show you can show different panels so you can toggle the layers
panel on and off here and you can toggle the entire user interface to show or hide.
So everything's hidden in kind of a full screen view here.
And then if you want to show just the outlines of your design you can click on this and it hides everything
else.
The styling shows you where the outlines are for your project.
And now the pixel preview option if you click on that I'm going to zoom in to illustrate this.
You can kind of see that everything looks sharp right here because it's vector.
But if I rotate this for example you can see that it starts to get blurry and that's because it's showing
us a preview of what it will look like if this vector was displayed on these pixels on a device.
You can also choose to show a transparency checkerboard and pretty much what this does is if there's
anything transparent inside of this frame or canvas it'll create a checkerboard showing you that it's
see through.
When you export it it's going to be transparent.
In this section we have a few zoom controls.
And next we can find the next art board and it'll switch over to the right or previous our board will
switch to the art board over to the left.
So if I click on this frame for example and I hold down option to duplicate it I have this frame selected
I can go into view and I can say I want to find the previous art board was going to jump to this one
on the left.
Next we can just enter full screen and I'll just zoom everything up to be front and center.
And now we have the object menu.
So let's zoom out here so we can see both of these boards I can click on object and this is where you
can group different selections or ungroup you can frame a selection.
So if I click on these two objects and choose frame selection you will wrap your objects around a frame
and this is a little bit different than grouping and I'll show you why in a future video.
Now we have a few component options and the great thing about component's is that it allows you to reuse
a symbol or a design throughout your entire project and to make quick changes very easily.
I'm going to cover this in a lot more detail in a future video but these options here will allow you
to create a component so it converts this frame into a component as you can see here.
And then here you can go to master component.
Now because we only have one master component here if I copy this 500 times let's say I can select one
of these copies I can jump in here and select go to master component and it'll just jump to that master
component so I can make those quick changes.
Also if I click on one of the child components and thereby change the color or the stroke to be different
than that Master component I can always click on this reset instance and it'll reset the style to what
the master component is.
Next let's say you have a master component and a few child components and one of the child components
you want to be able to edit the size in the stroke and everything and you don't want it to be affected
by the master component.
You can always detach this and convert it back into a frame where it's not a component by detaching
this from the master component.
Now I know this all probably sounds really confusing right now but don't worry because I'm going to
cover this in a future video.
This is the power of Sigma with components and collaborative editing and it's going to take a dedicated
video in itself to really explain how this works.
Now you have some other object settings so you can resize an object to fit inside of a frame and you
can toggle some object clipping to clip and be masked behind another object or not.
These options here allow you to bring objects back and forth in the layering scheme and to show you
that here I'm just going to click on this object I'm going to hold down option I'm going to drag this
to create a copy and you can obviously see this layer is on top of this layer here.
And so if I want to move this around in the layers panel I can click on send it back and I'll send this
to the very back or I can go to object and bring forward bring forward bring forward it'll bring that
forward three times and the layering scheme.
You have some quick flip options if you want to flip this horizontal you're vertically.
Some quick rotation options.
You can also flatten selection so you can see the selection also shows that it's rotated here.
But if I click on Flaten selection for example it's going to flatten this and now I have selection handles
that are parallel to my art board.
So the difference here if I click on this other object you can see the width is 150 pixels.
And now because the selection handle is contained perpendicular to my frame it shows that with as 175
pixels and there are some great reasons why you would want to do that for some particular objects but
just know that you have that ability here subsumed into my canvas here and now if I click on this rectangle
you can click on any rectangle you want inside of here as long as it has a stroke.
And now if I go into object and I click on this outline stroke what that does is converts this stroke
into an outline.
So if I click on this you can see now that I have this outline.
So now when I double click inside of here you can see that this isn't a stroke but it's actually a shape
that I can now manipulate the inside of the shape in the outside of this shape.
And this comes in handy sometimes because now when I realize this you can see that this stroke that
I've converted to an outline actually resizes with it a scroll down here and select this object.
Now I'm going to go back into object and we have some bullion options and I'm going to talk about this
in another video too.
But essentially you can join some selections together so if you have two rectangles if you click on
union it'll match those to be one shape or you can subtract one shape from another like a cookie cutter
method.
And there are a few other options here to manipulate these multiple objects to combined into one shape.
Now if you ever want to duplicate any objects in place you can hold down Kamandi or you can click this
duplicate selection in place and then you can delete raster selection.
If I click on this this turns a vector shape into a raster rise to a graphic.
So now this is an image and if I resize this image you can see the stroke get skewed and things start
to look a little bit weird here and I can also click on this filled image option here and change things
like the exposure the contrast saturation and any other image editing options.
Now clicking on this shape here I'm going to go into object and you can show or hightest selection.
So I click on this to hide it.
You can see that what that does is it toggles this little eyeball icon in the layers panel to show and
hide.
You can also lock or unlock a selection so you don't accidentally change it.
So this is hidden and locked but I can show it and have it still be locked so if I drag any rectangles
I'm never going to select that and I won't be able to edit this accidentally again this is just a toggle
button to unlock and lock through here.
And next you can select a few layers then you can click on hide other layers and it will hide everything
that's not selected.
Now if you ever want to quickly remove a file or remove a stroke or swap the fill and stroke these options
are here.
So now we have purple is the Phil Black as the stroke and we can just choose to remove the feel altogether.
And now if I drag this over some of these objects you can kind of see that the black is layered over
it but there is not any feel inside of there.
Now to show you some items in the vector menu but I'm going to do is just delete this frame here.
I'm going to drag this over and then just delete all the objects in here so I just have one blank frame.
And now this vector menu gives you some great options so I'll show you kind of how these work.
I'm going to click on the pen tool here and I'll show you this tool in more detail a little bit later
but let's say we have some weird shape here.
And I hit escape and say that I'm done.
Well what happens if we want to close this shape later.
What I can do is double click on this object and then I can choose this node here.
And if I hold down shift I can select this note as well.
And now I jump into vector I can join the selection which will interpret and just create a solid line
and between the two open paths.
But now if I click commands or control Z on Windows I can go back and Vector.
And now I can say I want a smooth join the selection which will interpret this and make the path really
smooth an other thing I may want to do is I can double click on this object again and let's say I don't
want this node inside of my selection here so I can select this note again go into vector and delete
and heal a selection and that will delete this node but it will also try to retain a similar shape that
that node was taking care of.
Sometimes when you use fewer nodes inside of your vector icons your curves become smoother and it feels
more organic.
So these three tools can be really powerful.
Now let's click done here and I'm going to just delete this shape and just for illustration purposes
I'm going to add some text.
We have a text box here.
I'm going to increase the size here to 48 so we can see it.
And now this text menu gives us a nice toggle bold taluk underline we can convert text to it's original
case or uppercase or lowercase.
Now this 4:03 layout option isn't something that you're hardly ever going to use if ever this force
is text objects in the collection to be laid out again if fonts you're using got updated it just verifies
that all the fonts are pre-rendered to make sure they're using the latest version of that font.
I've never used this yet.
I don't think you will either.
Now to show you some features in the arr. menu.
I'm going to create a few objects here so I'm just going to draw a few rectangles and hold down option.
Just copy this.
So we have four rectangles here.
If we select all of these we have some arr. options.
We can round two pixels to make sure that the sizes of these are on subpixel like 100 point five pixels.
So this will round them to whole pixels in case that accident ever happens.
And then you can arrange by aligning objects to the left.
We're going to click command Z here.
You can also align to top and you can also pack things so packing things horizontally fits each object
side by side packing them tightly so there's no margin between those objects.
Again you can pack these vertically and that will do the same thing making sure that they fit nice and
snug against each other vertically and then you have some distribute options so you can distribute horizontally
you can distribute to the top vertically or distribute bottom.
So these settings just help you arrange objects evenly or align them evenly with each other.
You can find a lot of those same options here as well.
Now under window we have some basic controls like minimize this window.
Zoom in to fill the entire screen.
You can also select previous and next tabs.
Here we only have one tab open but let's say you have three files open you can jump back and forth between
them.
With these options or you can bring all Sigma windows to the front inside help.
I really love this search inside the Mac help.
So if I want to find a certain feature in one of these menu options I can just type it in here like
outline and I can find this outline stroke option actually lives under object and right here so you
can quickly find the settings that you're looking for inside the menubar.
There's also some help in tutorial files and this is where you'll sign out of Sigma or you can toggle
developer tools on and off.
I've never used these it's basically just an inspector mode just like you'll see in Chrome.
So you'll get to see some of the H chainmail that makes up these objects here.
But again I've never used this and I don't think you will either.
So that's just a brief introduction of the menu items here.
We're going to go over a lot more of these in much more detail.
I know I went over them really fast.
It's just to get you basically introduced to some of these things so that you know where you can find
different options if you want to go out and design on your own and just play with it.
But again some of these options want a much more detailed video to explain so I'll do that in future
videos.