To show you the tools panel I'm going to start off with a fresh new project so to follow along.
Just start a new project and we can just work our way from there the first time I'm going to do in the
Tools menu is create a new frame and this frame tool is used to create new art boards and also to frame
certain sections like a navigation menu bar or an iPhone navigation footer to start off.
You can see here on the right we have different presets for frames that we want to create.
So I can create an iPhone X frame for example here and I can just click on that and it'll plop that
directly in the canvas or if I click on this frame tool I can drag and create a custom frame size at
whatever size that I want.
I'm going to delete this frame and let's just keep this iPhone X frame as we move along.
Now to select any objects you have this move tool this move and select.
So now I can click on the name of this frame and I can move it.
Now I want to create a few shapes So here's where you'll find your shapes.
I can quickly draw some rectangles here.
And if I click on this dropdown arrow I have more shape options so here I can draw an ellipse and I
can hold down shift to constrain this proportionately and I'll just drag this around.
And we have a few of these other one star tool polygon and you lips I'll just place these ones for now.
Now I can also scale these objects if I have this circle for example I can click on this down arrow
next to the move tool and I can click on the scale tool and I can just drag any one of these drag handles
and scale this down or up as I see fit.
Now those are great for simple shapes and I'm going to just select both of these and drag them up a
little bit.
But I can also create custom shapes using this pen tool.
For example if I want to quickly create a shape of a heart let's say I can do that here and I'll show
you more how to use these controls to create your own shapes.
I'm just drawing something quick to show you where these tools live and kind of how they work.
And you can see here when we're inside the pen tool we have other options here too.
So we can use this paint bucket tool for example to click and paint a certain color inside of that stroke
or that shape and we can also use this bend tool to select certain nodes and bend the shape.
If you want to design something more freeform like a signature for example you can use this down arrow
and select the pencil tool.
But before I do that I'm just going to click done here because I don't want to create the same shape
inside of this that instance.
So now I'm going to click on this down arrow and click on the pencil tool.
And here's where I can create a quick signature.
And I'm using a mouse so it's kind of messy.
But you can see how freeform that is.
And now when you double click inside of here you can still use these notes to edit and clean up the
pads here.
Now you'll find a basic text tool and this is where you can add different text so you can add a navigation
for example.
And another thing you can do with the text tool is instead of clicking to add some text you can click
and drag to create a bounding box that your text is going to wrap and live inside of.
Next we have the comment tool and this comment tool is really powerful because you can share your designs
with anybody on the web.
They don't have to install anything.
And they can quickly jump in and start commenting on your designs here so they can click on any area
here and say this circle needs some color.
And as soon as they click post I'll be notified of that and I can have a conversation directly in here
and I can hover over this to refer back to this conversation.
And now if I ever add some color I can just click this resolve and it'll archive that conversation so
I don't need to see it unless I pull up my archived conversation.
So it's really nice.
Now this center area right here is only showing the name of the file right now which is untitled.
This is where you can rename your file and you can also jump into version history to see what's been
going on through different versions.
So if I click Show version history you can see what it looks like at 4:16 p.m. or the current version
and I haven't done much in here so there's not many versions but this is where you'll find five 10 or
15 different versions throughout the last 30 days.
Now if I click back to editing here I can click back on this dropdown arrow.
I can duplicate this file.
I can delete this or jump back into my files or move this file to a certain project.
So that's where you'll find the controls for your file.
But watch what happens when I click on the circle.
All of a sudden I have some contextual options that allow me to edit this circle specifically.
So if you hover over this this is the option for editing an object so that click inside of here it will
show me the nodes and here's where I can drag some of these nodes around and edit the object.
I can click done here or I can reset the instance.
Now this is greyed out because this only applies to components which we're going to talk about later.
But let's say I create a component here and this component is created I'm going to just hold down option
and copy this master component and that creates a child component.
And again I'm going to talk more about how this works in a later video.
But now let's say I choose this card to be read and I choose this color it should be blue.
Well because this is a child component of this Master component I can click inside of here and I can
say I want to reset this instance to match the master component and that's what that does here.
Now if you want to mask any shapes with any other shapes or mask a shape with an image you can do this
here and I'll show you how this works by adding an image real quick and we'll mask that with this shape
here so we can go into the shapes tool click on place image.
And now if you visit the assets folder under the exorcized files you can click on any one of these images
or just find an image on your computer to upload here.
It doesn't matter which image.
So I'm going to click Open and now it's going to ask me where I want to place this and watch this if
I hover over this circle it will place the image and mask it inside of here or here or this shape.
But to maintain some masking control what I'm going to do is just click outside of any of these and
just click somewhere out of the canvas randomly.
And now that we have this image in place I can click on the image and resize this holding down shift
and I can resize it to fit somewhat within this rectangle behind it and I'm going to hold down Z and
drag a rectangle to zoom in here and zoom in I can select this rectangle hold down shift and select
the image.
And now I can click on this use as a mask tool and now this rectangle behind the image is purely a mask
that's masking the image above this so I can still click on this image layer.
I can do some resizing within here and move it around to exactly where I want and it will always be
masked within this rectangle.
Now I want to show you the bully on tool and in order to do that I'm just going to select everything
that I have here and just hit delete.
And here I'm just going to zoom in holding down the Z key and I'll just drag a rectangle right here.
And now I can add some different shapes here like a rectangle and a circle and now I'm going to change
the color of this one so you can kind of see which ones on top of each other.
Now using this bully on tool or this union selection I can select two of these shapes here and I can
click Union.
And that creates one shape where I can change the color of this one shape I can manipulate this as if
it's one.
But this bully on effect creates icons that are nondestructive so I can still double click inside of
here and I can move this around and manipulate this shape too.
For example be wider and centered within this square.
So you see you can create some great shapes using some simple squares and circles.
Now if I right click and ungroup here that will undo that change that I made and I can still select
both of these.
And here I can choose to subtract the one that's in front from the one that's behind.
And so now you can see that it kind of behaves as a cookie cutter holding down commands Z.
I can undo this.
And now I can intersect the selection so anything that's intersected in between these two shapes is
going to keep and excluding the selection retains the shape above here and the shape down here and anything
that's intersecting it kind of just subtracts that.
Now you've seen so far that we have nondestructive editing where I can still move this around and it
still retains the exclude feature but what happens if I want to bake this in now and do some further
editing.
So this acts like one image.
It is two different shapes.
I can go in here after I've edited everything and combined my shapes I can choose to flatten selection
and what that does now is as this is one single shape.
So now when I double click inside of here you can see that I can edit the nodes inside of here and now
I can't just grab this circle and move it like I was able to.
But now I'm able to do some more advanced techniques to kind of tweak the shape that I want.
The last one I want to show you is the crop image.
So again I'm going to go into the shapes tool click on place image and I'll grab one of these shapes
again and once I placed this here I can place it like I have before or I can click and drag a rectangle
and I can drag this to be the size that I want rather than just clicking in place as the original size.
So now I can click on this Krop image here and it gives me these nice crop marks where I can choose
to compose this image in whatever kind of frame that I want.
And once I hit return that's now cropped.
Now if I double click inside of here I can do that same masking technique.
And if I resize this a kind of skews the image within this cropped area.
Now those are all the object menus.
And lastly to the right we can see more options in the tools panel.
One of them is it's showing my named Caleb here because I'm actually logged in with two computers so
even though I'm using my same account if I'm logged in twice it'll show hey Caleb's here and another
computer too.
So if you have three or four or five people working on this project you're going to see those three
four or five icons here and you can click on one of those icons to actually see the other users mouse
and follow where they're designing.
Now if you want to share this project with anybody else you can click the share icon and you can share
this by just copying a link or even embedding a code inside of a blog for people to interact with your
designs within a blog like Wordpress.
Now we'll talk a little bit more about the present feature in a prototype video.
But if I click on this I get a nice preview of my design and if I've prototyped this I can click through
to interact with my design.
You can see that this present mode actually opens up in a new tab here so I can still toggle back and
edit a few things like move this over and jump back into the present mode and see that that changes
live.
Or I can just close it this way and jump back into it at any time here if I want to jump into my view
settings.
I can choose to toggle some pixel preview pixel grid layout grids.
So these are a few quick view options that you'll get here in the View menu as well and to the right
it shows you a few shortcuts to toggle these views on and off.
Now if you don't want to hold down Z to draw a rectangle to zoom in a certain area or if you don't want
to hold down command to zoom in and out you can choose some precise zoom controls by clicking on this
arrow here and jumping to 0 percent or 50 percent.
And there's also some short cuts here that you can use like the equal sign or the subtract sign to zoom
in and out.
Or if you want to zoom to fit you just tap 1 or 0 for 100 percent.
The last tool in the Tools panel is this export assets tool and you can see that it shows 0 out of 0
selected that I can't export anything.
And that's because before you export anything you have to actually select these objects and make them
exportable and decide what format you want to export them in.
So now that I clicked on that to make exportable let's say we have two or three or four different objects
I'm just going to add another circle here and I'll make this exportable as well.
So you have to exportable objects now and you can click on this export and you can see these two layers
and it's going to export both of them as a PMG.
Now you don't have the option to name these objects that are being exported in the export panel but
if you want this file to be named something differently you can click on it here and just double click
to change the name right here and you can name this cake.
For example you jump back in here you can see that that's named differently.