Talk you through the pages and layers panel let's open up this pages layer's file that you can find
in the exercise folder under Chapter 2.
And first off if you don't see this layer's panel it may be hidden so you can go in the View menu and
show layer's panel right here and this will toggle the layers panel on and off.
Now to show you this layer's panel I just want to hold down the Zeek and I'll draw a rectangle under
this log in page here just to zoom in a little bit.
And you can see first of all if you hover over different layers you can see that those layers are shown
in the canvas as well in blue.
And each layer has an icon here to the left of it to indicate what this layer is for.
So for example this text layer is a group of all of these text objects here and that's indicated by
a dashed line.
And then we also have frames.
So the log in page home page menu.
These are all frames that group the objects inside of this device preview.
Now frames can also be inside of frames.
For example if you click on this your art museum frame here we can see that this is app info that's
inside of the log in page frame.
And one nice thing with working with Sigma is for example by click outside of this frame here and I
go into this home frame let's scroll over and I can click on Masters old and new as soon as I do that
then everything drops down and expands to show me these objects within this frame itself.
Now if you want to keep things clean after you're done working with for example the home frame you can
click on this little arrow and it'll collapse all of the layers underneath this home frame.
And so you can collapse and expand anything that's grouped like frames.
This is a component here.
And groups now Master components are what you can use to create a design and reuse it throughout your
project.
And we'll talk about that more in a future video.
But this behaves much like a group as well where you'll have objects underneath this master component.
Now within any of these layers like this app info layer you can click and drag this down throughout
the hierarchy to move this down in the layers panel.
So right now this is behind the background image.
And so I can move this down or move this back up where it belongs where you can see this.
You can also move layers onto different art boards or frames by clicking and holding if you hold then
it'll expand the layers underneath this frame and I can click and let go.
And now this is inside of another layer.
I'm going to click command z a few times to undo this and now another thing that you get with layers
if you write clicks you have a number of different menu items to manipulate these layers so you can
send them forward and back in the later scheme.
You can group certain selections if you select multiple layers you have the option to show and hide
a layer or lock and unlock where you can flip them or copy and paste certain styles.
Now to show and hide or lock and unlock layers you also have some icons here if you hover over any layer
you can quickly click this lock icon.
And now if I click anywhere within this area I'm not able to select this.
Your art museum layer but I can select any layers underneath this.
So it's a great feature if you still want to see the objects in front of other objects but you want
to reach out to the elements behind to interact with them.
You can also toggle this icon to hide your layers and if you do hide this layer you can still expand
this layer and you can see that there are some nested layers here that are also hidden and that's indicated
by this door saying I'm adopting the same hidden property that you have applied to the parent layer
so working with layers is really great.
But what happens when you have a lot of frames and a lot of layers within one page.
Well we have the pages panel as well this shows page one here and there's only one page right now in
this project.
And I can show you how pages works.
If I hit the one key I'm going to zoom out here to show all of these art boards and let's say I want
to organize some of these boards in different pages.
So if I want to do that I can click on this page one here and you can see that I get a little dropdown
to create a new page.
So I'm going to create a page called collections.
And now to go back to page 1 I can select any frame that I want or any objects that I want and if I
right click I can move this to the page collections.
I can also just command X here and go into the collections page and command V for a quick cut and paste
or copy and paste in between pages.
Now one really nice way that I like to use pages is I always create a page within my project called
archive land and I use this archive land page for different designs that I might want to archive but
aren't necessarily a part of the current design.
For example if I hold the key and zoom into this home frame here and I'll hold down a command and just
scroll down just so I can see a little bit above here too I can click on this home frame and hold down
option and if I hold down option I can drag this up to create a copy.
And now I can make a number of changes to this and if I like this change I want to commit to this I
can save this in my current design but to keep this page clean I can just right click here and move
this to archive land.
And I know that I have access if I want to refer to that later but I can commit this frame to my current
design.