To show you how Team libraries works I need to first show you how to add a new team into figure.
So down here when the very first start up figure in the start screen we have this new teen icon.
And here you can name your team and if you go through this process there will be options to invite new
members to the team.
Because I already went through this I'm going to click Cancel and I have enabled a paid account under
the team brain spin so I can show you this feature.
Now if you're working with the free account you don't have access to the team libraries so you won't
be able to follow along with me.
But I'll still be able to explain kind of how Team libraries works and how the panels works.
And if you do have a paid subscription plan.
Feel free to just add a team and then click.
New project here and I'm just going to call this project bootstrap styles and I'll click Create project
here.
And once I have this project set up I can import my file here.
And let's import the bootstrap underscore styles fig file and now we can open up this bootstrap styles
fig file and we can see a number of buttons that were designed for bootstrap.
So now that we're in a team and we have these buttons designed Let's say you want to use these across
multiple files and share these designs with the team so they can use these buttons throughout their
project.
Well first thing I'll do is click on this components panel here we can see that they're not set up as
a component yet.
So what we would do is click on each of these elements and just click Create component and you can see
there's a button primary there's a button secondary and just go through here and click on the Create
component for each of these in the top row.
So now we have these components set up and here we can start with the primary button here.
If I right click I can publish this one component to the team library and if I click on that we can
see that.
Now this is in the team library section and I can always remove this from the library.
But what does that mean.
Now this is added in a library in the library's panel.
Well I can click down here and I can see that we have this file called Bootstrap styles and by clicking
here we have that one button we can reuse throughout multiple files.
Well I'll go back here into the components panel and I'll just click this info and I'll add this to
the library.
Well let's just add them all.
So now we have these all added to the library and we can see a little sync icon here saying they've
been added but they haven't been published yet.
So if I go to any other file and try to access these I'm not going to be able to find them so I'll just
click this publish and it'll give me a view of everything that's going to be added to the library.
And so I'll click publish changes and now these are all added to the team library.
So now all I have to do is click on the plus icon to create a whole new file.
And as I'm designing I can click to create a new frame here and I'll go to a desktop and create a desktop
frame.
And so now there's somebody else on my team may have created and shared those styles.
I can jump here to the team library and jump in to bootstrap styles and say I guess I want this primary
but I want to use this throughout my project here.
So if I hold down option I can copy this three times here and now that I have these inside my file I
can still double click on these and let's click on the layers panel so we can see how these look here.
So I still see this background.
I can see the text and I can change this text too quick on me.
I can resize those and if I want to change the look of this I can click this go to master component
and it will jump into this project where the master component is.
And here I can double click inside of here to change this to green for example and I can go back into
my project.
And nothing's changed yet.
But if I go back into this bootstrap styles you can see that it's shown here that I've changed the style
but I haven't published the change.
So as soon as I click publish or of any team members click publish then it's going to tell me this is
going to be updated in the library from blue to green so I could publish change here and we'll click
on untitled and everything is still blue.
But you notice here on the bottom right we have an alert that says component updates available so I
can click dismiss her review here and I'll click dismiss right now.
And one thing that's really nice is you're not surprised by some quick changes by team members and you
don't have to adopt those changes that they created.
But if we ever wanted to adopt those changes later we can click on this team library panel here and
let's kick this back button and we can see that there's one update available.
So click on that update and it will tell me this button primary and bootstrap change to green here.
So I'll decide I want to update this to just click update and now everything's changed to green.
It still has that blue stroke so I'll go back in here and I'll double click on this again change this
blue stroke to maybe the same maybe a light green stroke or a dark green stroke.
Let's just do that.
Same thing here publish the change not published we can go back into our other project and we can click
review immediately this time and update all changes.
So the power behind Team libraries is you can have one team member that is designing all of the styles
for a certain project or for multiple projects and at the same time you can have somebody else working
on the project itself adopting those styles dragging them in and applying those.
And then they can decide whether to adopt changes later as the style grows.
So it's a great way to reuse styles and elements not just in your project like Master component's allows
but throughout multiple projects and throughout the entire team.