Congratulations on finishing this film of course by now you should have your first completed and interactive
design inside figment.
It means the world to me that you've made it this far and that you trusted me to help you learn things.
Do you ever have any further questions you can always follow me on social sites or reach out to me using
the instructor messaging platform.
I would love to hear your thoughts about this course and how it can improve as I'm constantly updating
the videos as new features are released.
Also if you could find the time to leave a review it really helps improve the visibility of this course
and helps me fund future course videos.
Thanks and I look forward to helping you further in the future.