This course has broken down into multiple sections.
We'll first learn how to navigate around the interface and in the next section will begin setting up
our project.
Next we will be adding content into our artworks and then we'll complete the design using the skills
that we've learned in previous sections after the design is complete.
We'll move on to prototyping and sharing our design and I'll lead off with some resources that you can
use to continue learning and designing with Figma.
This course is designed to walk you through designing your recipe from scratch.
But if you ever want to jump into future videos and of course there are exercise files included to start
wherever you'd like.