As we go through the videos in this course I may introduce certain files that we want to start out with
and you can download these exercise files in Udemy. if you're watching this in Udemy, you can
click this menu button to open up the coarse sections and this is where you will download the exercise
files to follow along.
This is what the exercise files folder looks like.
And you can see to the very left we have an assets folder.
If we double click inside of here this is where we're going to see all of our images and text files.
And these are things that we're going to import into our projects.
But if you're following along in specific chapters I may introduce a new file at the beginning of the
video in the bottom left corner.
And if you follow that path you can click inside of the folder and this is where the files are going
to live.
If you want to start off with the same file I'm using in the video.
Now once we begin designing the recipe app you will be able to start your own file and follow along
with me without having to download each file for each video.
If you do skip some videos However I recommend that you start with the latest file inside of one of
these folders as you work through the design with me in the video.